<resources>

    <!-- GENERAL PURPOSE NAMES PLANET NAMES -->

    <string name="app_name">Solar System Guide</string>
    <string name="the_sun">The Sun</string>
    <string name="mercury">Mercury</string>
    <string name="venus">Venus</string>
    <string name="earth">Earth</string>
    <string name="mars">Mars</string>
    <string name="jupiter">Jupiter</string>
    <string name="saturn">Saturn</string>
    <string name="uranus">Uranus</string>
    <string name="neptune">Neptune</string>
    <string name="pluto">Pluto</string>
    <string name="eris">Eris</string>
    <string name="ceres">Ceres</string>
    <string name="dwarfs">Dwarfs</string>
    <string name="others">Others</string>
    <string name="check_out">Choose the body you\'d like to check out</string>
    <string name="learn_more">Learn more</string>
    <string name="placeholder">placeholder</string>
    <string name="atmosphere">Atmosphere</string>
    <string name="sizes_and_distances">Sizes and distances</string>
    <string name="orbit_and_rotation">Orbit and rotation</string>
    <string name="internal_structure">Internal structure</string>
    <string name="history_of_the_body">History of the body</string>
    <string name="ended_missions">Ended missions</string>
    <string name="ongoing_missions">Ongoing missions</string>

    <!-- STRINGS FOR THE DETAILS OF THE SUN -->

    <string name="ended_sun_mission_count">14 missions ended, including 1 failure</string>
    <string name="ongoing_sun_mission_count">7 missions ongoing</string>
    <string name="sun_rundown">Largest, and most massive object within our solar system, containing 99.8% of overall mass, \nOfficially classified as a yellow dwarf, the Sun is a comparatively small star
        \nThe oldest body in our solar system at 4.6 billion years old.</string>
    <string name="sun_sizes_and_distances_text">The Sun has a radius of 695,508 kilometers(432,168.6 miles).
        \nWhile our star isn\'t among the biggest around it\'s still very massive, 332,946 times more so than Earth.
        \nIt\'s 150 million kilometers (93 million miles) away from Earth.
        \nThe nearest interstellar neighbor of our solar system is Alpha Centauri, 4.37 light years away.</string>
    <string name="orbit_and_rotation_sun_text">As a non-solid body different parts of the Sun rotate at different rates, at the equator one rotation takes 25 Earth days, at the poles that same action takes 36 days.
        \nOur solar system is moving at 720,000 kilometers per hour(450,000 miles per hour). Even at that speed it takes around 230 million years to make a full rotation around the Milky Way.</string>
    <string name="interstellar_distance_map">Interstellar distance map</string>
    <string name="history_of_the_sun_text">The Sun was formed alongside the rest of our solar system, around 4.5 billion years ago.
        \nWhile forming it took over big majority of the material ending up with 99.8% of the entire combined mass of our solar system.
        \nThe scientists calculated that our parent star should be around for another 6.5 billion years, ending up as a white dwarf.</string>
    <string name="internal_structure_of_the_sun">The Sun is composed mainly of two elements hydrogen (which takes up 91% of overall composition) and helium (which takes up 8.9%).
        \nIt consists of six regions: the core, the radiative zone, and the convective zone in the interior,the surface (photosphere), the chromosphere and the corona.
        \nThe temperature in the core reaches 15 million degrees C (27 million degrees F), high enough to sustain the process of nuclear fusion
        \nThe temperature on the surface drops down to 5 500 degrees C (10 000 degrees F), while 3000 times smaller than the temperature of the core it\'s still enough to make carbon (like diamonds or graphite) boil.</string>
    <string name="the_inside_of_the_sun">The inside of the sun</string>
    <string name="atmosphere_of_the_sun">The atmosphere of our parent star is relatively thin, within that region are where we can find the sunspots and solar flairs.
    \nWhat\'s interesting about that region is that the temperature once again rises up to 2 million degrees C (3.5 million degrees F), the source of that heat remains unknown.</string>


    <!-- FINISHED SOLAR PROBE MISSIONS -->

    <string name="pioneer_program">Pioneer program</string>
    <string name="pioneer_program_text">\n<b>Pioneer 5</b>
        \n\nA spin-stabilized probe originally meant to study Venus with a flyby, after some launch complications the mission profile changed to observe the space in between the orbits of Venus and Earth,
        active for just over 100 days Pioneer 5 has confirmed the existence of interplanetary magnetic fields among other accomplishments.
        \n\n<b>Pioneer 6-9</b>
        \n\nLaunched in the years of 1965-1968 they were, akin to their earlier sibling, a series of spin-stabilized probes that were meant to study the Sun and they did so with plenty of success.
        The first of the series, 6, was successfully contacted in 2000, 7 was last contacted in 1995 wherein it was confirmed that one of its scientific instruments were still running,
        8 in 1996, like the previous one, with one instrument functioning and finally 9 lost contact in 1983, in 1987 it was attempted to reconnect but the attempt failed and the spacecraft was declared inactive.
        \n\n<b>Pioneer E</b>
        \n\nPioneer E was supposed to be the fifth probe following the Pioneer 6-9 but due to a hydraulic failure the rocket was destroyed by range safety.</string>
    <string name="helios_program">\nHelios program</string>
    <string name="helios_program_text">\n<b>Helios 1</b>
        \n\nThe probe was launched on 10th of November 1974 constructed in FRG(Federal Republic of Germany or West Germany) on US-built launch vehicles it was designed, same as its sibling, to observe solar wind,
        magnetic fields and cosmic rays. The data from the probe was received in a German control center up until 1982.
        \n\n<b>Helios 2</b>
        \n\nThe probe launched on 15th of January 1976 it flew considerably closer to our parent star, 3 million kilometers (1.9 million miles) closer in fact. The probe gave us valuable insight to the solar plasma,
        cosmic rays and cosmic dust until contact was lost in 1980 when the transmitter aboard the craft failed. The probe was shut down in 1982 to prevent any possible radio interference with future missions.</string>
    <string name="isee_program">\nISEE program</string>
    <string name="isee_program_text">\nISEE program was an international multipurpose effort consisting of 3 spacecraft, ISEE-1 and ISEE-2 were orbiting earth while ISEE-3 went to the L1 equilibrium point between Earth and the Sun
        being the first probe to achieve that.
        \n\nISEE-3 has monitored the incoming solar wind from 1978 to 1981, successfully completing all its objectives before NASA decided to extend its mission steering it to research the Earth magnetic tail as well as the first ever flyby of a comet.
        The extended mission ended in 1997, though the transmitter was left on and the orbit meant the probe would periodically flyby Earth. In 2014 fully crowd-funded efforts were made to recapture it, but they failed from lack of propellant.</string>
    <string name="ulysses_program">\nUlysses program</string>
    <string name="ulysses_program_text">\nUlysses probe launched from the cargo bay of the space shuttle Discovery in 1990 after considerable delay because of the Challenger disaster, leaving Earth at an escape velocity reaching 15 kilometers per second
        (10 miles per second) fastest of any man-made object up to that point.
        \n\nIt has visited Jupiter and researched the Jovian system before continuing on to study the Sun, following a polar orbit it has observed the different speeds of solar wind when comparing equatorial regions and the poles,
        showed the periodic reversal of magnetic poles as well as accidentally passed through 3 separate comet tails. The probe has gone through 3 revelations around our parent star with the data stream steady until 2008.
        The program was declared finished in 2009 when the probe fuel supply froze over due to the decaying of its electrical systems, 18 years after launch and more than 4 times the first intended length of the effort.</string>
    <string name="stereo_program">\nStereo program</string>
    <string name="stereo_program_finished_text">\nThe Stereo program consisted of 2 twin satellites, Stereo A and Stereo B, designed to orbit ahead and behind the Earth to capture the Sun from more angles than ever before, with both probes slowly moving apart.
        The mission provided valuable insight into solar flares as well as detailed maps of the solar surface, in 2011 the spacecraft were at an exact opposite points in their orbits giving a 360 degree view of the Sun, the first and so far only observation of its kind.
        Both probes had some issues with Solar activity routinely interfering with the devices.
        \n\nIn October 2014 contact was lost with Stereo B following a planned restart, after which reconnection was attempted once every month or so, the probe was back
        in contact August-September 2016 but a fix couldn\'t be deployed to restore the functionality and since then Stereo B has been silent with NASA declaring it dead in 2018.
        \n\nStereo A continues to function as of 2019. Check ongoing missions tab for detailed information.</string>


    <!-- ONGOING SOLAR PROBE MISSIONS -->


    <string name="wind_program">Wind</string>
    <string name="wind_program_text">\nLaunched on the 1st of November 1994 Wind was a part of international cooperation between USA, Japan and the European Space Agency, the International Solar Terrestrial Physics program (ISTP).
        It\'s intended target, the L1 Lagrange point between the Sun and Earth took until 1996, the reason being Wind was not the only spacecraft heading in that direction, with SOHO and ACE missions doing the same, while on hold
        it has conducted some magnetosphere research. It has done 19 lunar flybys, using the gravity assists to maintain the apogee of the orbit above the day hemisphere.
        \n\nWhen it got to its intended location Wind provided about an hour of warning about the state of solar wind for other ISTP spacecraft. In November 1998 Wind has begun a series of maneuvers to stray from the ecliptic plane,
        reaching 60 degrees deviation at most and giving us insight to the up to then unresearched regions of interplanetary space. It has returned to its intended position in 2004 where it has remained.
        \n\nDespite the programs conclusion in 2001 Wind continues to function, with predictions that it could stay at L1 for another 60 years. It plays a supporting role for other spacecraft researching our parent star.</string>
    <string name="soho_program">\nSOHO</string>
    <string name="soho_program_text">\nThe SOHO probe (Solar and Heliospheric Observatory) is an ESA sponsored contribution to the ISTP. It carries 12 instruments to study solar atmosphere, helioseismology and the solar wind.
        \n\nLaunched on 2nd of December 1995 it inserted into orbit around the L1 Lagrange point between the Sun and Earth on the 14th of February 1996. Communications were cut for 4 months starting in June 1998, after contact was regained
        in September the spacecraft was apparently spinning, not pointing at the sun. By September 25th the probe was back in control, with the loss of 3 of its onboard instruments.
        \n\nSOHO made several noteworthy discoveries, including locating the source of high-speed solar wind to the corners of the honeycomb shaped magnetic fields near the Sun\'s poles. Another one was the fact that by 2015,
        after 20 years of continuous work, SOHO has found over 3000 different comets, over half of what comets we know of by far. One of those comets were observed by the probe hurling at the Sun at the speed of 2.1 million kilometers per hour (1.3 million miles per hour).</string>
    <string name="ace_program">\nACE</string>
    <string name="ace_program_text">\nThe ACE probe (Advanced Composition Explorer) was designed to study spaceborne energy particles and establish commonalities between the Sun, Earth and Milky Way galaxy. \n\nIt has launched on the August
        25th 1997 and reached its intended position, the L1 point, in January 1998. Since then ACE has contributed near instant, constant stream of data regarding its results with all but one instrument functional. \n\nThe propellant on board
        theoretically could make the mission keep going until around 2024.</string>
    <string name="stereo_program_ongoing_text">\nThe Stereo program consisted of 2 twin satellites, Stereo A and Stereo B, designed to orbit ahead and behind the Earth to capture the Sun from more angles than ever before, with both probes slowly moving apart.
        The mission provided valuable insight into solar flares as well as detailed maps of the solar surface, in 2011 the spacecraft were at an exact opposite points in their orbits giving a 360 degree view of the Sun, the first and so far only observation of its kind.
        Both probes had some issues with Solar activity routinely interfering with the devices.
        \n\nIn July 2012 STEREO A was able to record the biggest stellar storm in over 150 years, collecting significant data in the process. In March 2015 STEREO A has been put into safe mode while the probe was passing on the far side of the Sun, obstructing it and making contact impossible.
        In July 2015 STEREO A has been back in contact with Earth and has continued to function since.
        \n\nStereo B\'s mission was declared finished in 2018. Check ended missions tab for detailed information.</string>
    <string name="dscovr_probe">\nDSCOVR</string>
    <string name="dscovr_probe_text">\nLaunched on February 11th 2015 DSCOVR (Deep Space Climate Observatory) is an American satellite providing real time solar wind observation as well as bihourly pictures of Earth from the L1 point where
        it has orbited since June 8th 2015.
        \n\nIn October 2015 a website was launched publishing some of the photos the probe takes of Earth with its camera, that same month DSCOVR was transferred from NASA to NOAA’s Space Weather Prediction Center (SWPC).</string>
    <string name="parker_solar_probe">\nParker Solar Probe</string>
    <string name="parker_solar_probe_text">\nThe Parker Solar Probe, launched August 12th 2018, is en route to be the closest man-made object to the Sun, aiming at the closest approach to reach within 6.2 million kilometers (3.9 million miles)
        from our parent star surface, the record holder so far Helios 2 reached 43 million kilometers (27 million miles).
        \n\nThe mission is planned to orbit the Sun 24 times in the span on 7 years, giving us insight to the reason why the Solar Corona is so hot, how the solar wind accelerates as well as the source of high-energy solar particles.
        \n\nPSP has reached its first approach on the 17th of January 2021, coming into 13.5 million kilometers (8.5 million miles) of the Sun\'s surface. This distance will decrease with each pass, using Venus for gravity assists.</string>
    <string name="solar_probe">\nSolar probe</string>
    <string name="solar_probe_text">\nLaunched in February 2020 the Solar Probe is supposed to complete over 20 orbits on polar trajectory around the Sun taking pictures of the poles letting us understand the solar cycle, mysterious heat of the corona,
        as well as the acceleration of solar wind and how they affect our planet.
        \n\nThe orbit trajectory will be changed with gravity assists of Venus, the first of which happened on the 27th of December 2020. The start of the primary mission is projected to November 2021.</string>

    <!-- STRINGS FOR THE DETAILS OF MERCURY -->

    <string name="ended_mercury_mission_count">2 missions ended</string>
    <string name="ongoing_mercury_mission_count">1 mission ongoing</string>
    <string name="mercury_rundown">The planet closest to the Sun, orbiting it at around 0.4 AU. \nSecond hottest planet of the solar system.
        \nMercury orbits our parent star once every 88 Earth days</string>
    <string name="mercury_sizes_and_distances_text">Mercury has a radius of 2,440 kilometers(1,516 miles), a little over 1/3 of Earth\'s radius.
        \nMercury\'s weight is only 6% of that of Earth, the density of the two planets are much close, with less than 0.1 grams per cubic centimeter of difference.
        \nOn average Mercury is 77 million kilometers(48 million miles) away from Earth.
        \nThe distance between it and the sun varies between 47 million kilometers (29 million miles) and 70 million kilometers (43 million miles).</string>
    <string name="orbit_and_rotation_mercury_text">Being so close to the Sun and spinning around it so quickly Mercury takes 88 Earth days to get around its orbit, one Solar day takes 176 Earth days thanks to the slow rotation on its axis.
        \nMercury moves at the speed of 47 kilometers (29 miles) per second, faster than any other planet in our solar system.</string>
    <string name="history_of_mercury_text">Mercury is around 4.5 billion years old, forming alongside other bodies in our solar system.
        \nOne of 5 planets visible with the naked eye Mercury was known all the way in ancient times, with the first written record from Babylon calling it Nabu.
        \nThe first observations with a telescope was done with Galileo in the 17th century.</string>
    <string name="internal_structure_of_mercury">Mercury has a large metallic core, the same as the other 3 rocky planets, that takes up about 85% of the planets radius.
        \nThere is evidence that it could be partly molten or fully liquid.
        \nThe surface of the planet, or the crust, is only 400 km (250 miles) thick.</string>
    <string name="the_inside_of_mercury">The inside of mercury</string>
    <string name="atmosphere_of_mercury">Instead of an atmosphere Mercury has an exosphere, an area around a body where particles are bound to it gravitationally but not densely enough to be considered a gas.</string>

    <!-- STRINGS FOR ENDED MERCURY MISSIONS-->

    <string name="mariner_10_title">Mariner 10</string>
    <string name="mariner_10_text">\nMariner 10 was the first spacecraft to research Mercury, the first mission to explore two planets (Mercury and Venus) in a single mission, the first to use a gravity assist to change its flight path, the first to make more than one pass on its target after initial encounter, and the first to use the solar wind as a major means of spacecraft orientation during flight.
        \n\nIt showed that Mercury\'s surface looked much like our Moon\'s, with plenty of craters, as well as brought conclusive evidence of lack of atmosphere around the planet.
        \n\nLaunching on November 3rd 1973 the probe did 3 flybys of Mercury as well as a flyby of Venus, returning thousands of pictures of both (over 4000 of Venus and more than 2700 of Mercury).
        \n\nOn the closest approach to Mercury Mariner 10 was only 327 kilometers (200 miles) away from the surface. 8 days after that contact was lost for good, this would be the last probe to visit Mercury for 3 decades.</string>
    <string name="messenger_title">\nMESSENGER</string>
    <string name="messenger_text">\nMESSENGER (Mercury Surface, Space Environment, Geochemistry and Ranging), launched August 3rd 2004 was the first spacecraft to successfully orbit Mercury, it did so in 2011.
        \n\nThe length of the trip was due to the propellant saving measures taken by the mission control, it consisted of using 1 Earth flyby, 2 Venus flybys and 3 Mercury flybys to nullify the acceleration resulting from getting closer to the Sun.
        \n\nMESSENGER has returned over 100 000 pictures, including one of Earth and Moon, plenty of surface pictures of Mercury, photographs of 2 comets, as well as, probably the most impressive, a mosaic of our solar system with every planet visible, short of Uranus and Neptune.
        \n\nThe spacecraft\'s mission ended in 2015 when it crashed into the surface of Mercury after it ran out of propellant to keep its orbit up, creating a new crater on the planet\'s surface.</string>

    <!-- STRINGS FOR ONGOING MERCURY MISSIONS-->

    <string name="bepicolombo">BepiColombo</string>
    <string name="bepicolombo_text">BepiColombo, named after an Italian mathematician and engineer Professor Giuseppe (Bepi) Colombo (1920–1984) from the University of Padua, Italy. It is a joint mission between ESA and Japan
        meant to study the composition, geophysics, atmosphere, magnetosphere and history of Mercury.
        \n\nThe spacecraft launched on the 20th of October 2018, with the plan of 1 flyby of Earth, 2 flybys of Venus and 6 flybys of Mercury before inserting into an orbit around 2025 with official mission starting early in the following year.
        \n\nThe latest milestone in October 2020 was the first successful flyby of Venus of the spacecraft.
        \n\nThis mission is the first time ESA and Japan journey to Mercury, as well as the first Mercurial mission to consist of two separate orbiters meant to operate independently.</string>

    <!-- STRINGS FOR THE DETAILS OF VENUS -->

    <string name="ended_venus_mission_count">42 missions ended (including 19 failures)</string>
    <string name="ongoing_venus_mission_count">1 missions ongoing</string>
    <string name="venus_rundown">Second planet in our solar system, but the hottest of all, Venus is the brightest of any planet of our solar system.
        \nIt has thick atmosphere full of gasses creating a greenhouse effect raising the temperature and pressure on the surface to the extreme
        \nOne of two planets, the other being Uranus, to orbit differently on its axis than every other planet in the system.</string>
    <string name="venus_sizes_and_distances_text">With a radius of 6,052 kilometers (3,760 miles) Venus is only slightly smaller than Earth, by mere 300 kilometers.
        \nThe average distance between it and the Sun is 108 million kilometers (67 million miles).</string>
    <string name="orbit_and_rotation_venus_text">One full orbit takes around 225 Earth days.
        \nThe rotation on its axis is going with the direction of its stellar orbit, opposite of how all other planets are, making the Venusian day into one of the longest in our solar system, 117 Earth days for a full solar day to go by.
        \nVenus orbits on the most circular orbit in our solar system, being a near perfect circle while every other body has more of an oval shaped orbit.
        \nIts axial tilt is only 3 degrees meaning there are no seasons.</string>
    <string name="history_of_venus_text">Venus is around 4.5 billion years old, forming alongside other bodies in our solar system.
        \nOne of 5 planets visible with the naked eye Venus was known all the way in ancient times, with the written record from Babylon in 1600 BC describing appearances of the planet over the course of 21 years.
        \nThe first observations with a telescope was done with Galileo in the 17th century. He discovered that Venus has phases similar to the Moon.</string>
    <string name="internal_structure_of_venus">Venus, like other terrestrial planets, has a metallic core about 3200 km (2000 miles) thick with a liquid mantle above it.
        \nThe surface of the planet is full of volcanoes, new ones being constantly produced through the thin, bulging surface of the planet.
        \nVenus has plenty of valleys and mountains, the tallest of which (Maxwell Montes), is 8.8 kilometers high (20,000 feet).</string>
    <string name="the_inside_of_venus">The inside of Venus</string>
    <string name="atmosphere_of_venus">Venus\' atmosphere consists mainly of CO2, trapping the sunlight and heating up the surface of the planet to a scorching 470 degrees Celsius (880 degrees Fahrenheit).
        \nAround 50 kilometers (20 miles) up the temperature drops to more or less what it is on the surface of Earth.
        \nThe winds of the atmosphere are just as extreme, with the very top layer of clouds being carried as fast as 360 kilometers (224 miles) per hour, accompanied by lightning bolts.
        \nThe pressure on the surface would be equivalent to being 1.6 kilometers (1 mile) underwater.</string>

    <!--STRINGS FOR THE PAST MISSIONS TO VENUS-->

    <string name="sputnik_7">Sputnik 7</string>
    <string name="sputnik_7_text">\nLaunched by USSR on 4th of February 1961 the craft failed to leave Earth orbit due to an issue with the upper stage, crashing back into our planet shortly after launch.</string>
    <string name="venera_1">\nVenera 1</string>
    <string name="venera_1_text">\nLaunched by USSR on 19th of May 1961 the probe was successful in leaving Earth\'s orbit, but the contact was lost after a week. It\'s speculated that the probe flied by Venus, the first man made object to flyby another planet.</string>
    <string name="mariner_1">\nMariner 1</string>
    <string name="mariner_1_text">\nLaunched by USA on 22nd of July 1962 the craft was destroyed by range safety after mere 4 minutes of flight, the blame was located on a faulty antenna as well as a single missing subscript bar. 
        The media would call the incident "The most expensive hyphen in history".</string>
    <string name="sputnik_19">\nSputnik 19</string>
    <string name="sputnik_19_text">\nLaunched by USSR on 25th of August 1962 the probe got into orbit around Earth but following a failure of one of the parts the main engine shut down after 45 seconds of what was intended to be a 4 minute burn. It reentered the atmosphere a couple days later.</string>
    <string name="mariner_2">\nMariner 2</string>
    <string name="mariner_2_text">\nLaunched by USA on 27th of August 1962, just 36 days after the failure of Mariner 1, it was the first successful interplanetary mission. It performed a flyby over Venus returning valuable data on the Venusian atmosphere, magnetosphere and temperatures.</string>
    <string name="sputnik_20">\nSputnik 20</string>
    <string name="sputnik_20_text">\nLaunched by USSR on 1st of September 1962 it reached Earth orbit, the main engine of the upper stage failed to ignite dooming the rocket to come back to the surface a few days after it launched.</string>
    <string name="sputnik_21">\nSputnik 21</string>
    <string name="sputnik_21_text">\nLaunched by USSR on 12th of September 1962 it got to orbit around Earth. One of the assisting engines exploded causing the rocket to lose control, forming bubbles in the main tank that made the main engine turn off less than a second after it started to fire.
        The probe returned to the ground after a few days.</string>
    <string name="kosmos_27">\nKosmos 27</string>
    <string name="kosmos_27_text">\nLaunched by USSR on 27th of March 1964, reaching Earth orbit. A circuitry design flaw prevented energy from being sent to attitude control thrusters causing the mission to fail, the spacecraft came back down on the following day.</string>
    <string name="zond_1">\nZond 1</string>
    <string name="zond_1_text">\nLaunched on the 2nd of April 1964 by USSR, it successfully left Earth orbit and headed for Venus. The spacecraft\'s launch vehicle performed without any failure, alas one of the sensor windows cracked causing a slow leak of air.
        The loss of pressure caused the electronic circuits to overheat, contact to the main module was lost shortly after. The mission could still be contacted via the lander module and a correction burn was executed but it was short by about 20 meters per second,
        causing the mission to miss its intended target. By May 14th all communication with the craft failed.</string>
    <string name="kosmos_96">\nKosmos 96</string>
    <string name="kosmos_96_text">\nLaunched on 23rd of November 1964 by USSR, reaching Earth orbit one of the fuel lines ruptured causing an explosion that made it impossible to control the craft, the orbit decayed fully on 9th of December 1964.</string>
    <string name="venera_2">\nVenera 2</string>
    <string name="venera_2_text">\nLaunched on 12th of November 1965 by USSR, it successfully reached Venus, performed a flyby and recorded all information. While the data was being gathered contact had to be cut, with the intention of it returning after
        the probe concluded its research. The contact was never recovered, the spacecraft was declared as lost on 3th of March 1966.</string>
    <string name="venera_3">\nVenera 3</string>
    <string name="venera_3_text">\nLaunched on 16th of November 1965 by USSR, it was the first spacecraft to impact the surface of another planet, having successfully steered into Venus. The original intent of the mission was to have a controlled landing,
        however contact was lost on 15th of February 1966, with the impact taking place on the 1st of March that same year. The cause for the loss of contact is suspected to be overheating.</string>
    <string name="venera_4">\nVenera 4</string>
    <string name="venera_4_text">\nLaunched on 12th of June 1967 by USSR, it was the first spacecraft to successfully breach another planet\'s atmosphere and transmit the data back to Earth. The probe collected data about the atmosphere pressure, composition,
        temperature as well as Venus\' magnetosphere. It has been built to make water landing possible, not knowing what to expect on the surface of Venus. The craft entered Venusian atmosphere on 18th of October 1967.
        The probe lost contact with Earth before it could reach the surface of the planet. The data that it did send back caused quite the controversy, as it was so different from what was expected some data, like the composition of the atmosphere, has been contested by some scientists.</string>
    <string name="mariner_5">\nMariner 5</string>
    <string name="mariner_5_text">\nLaunched on 14th of June 1967 by USA, initially the craft was a backup for Mariner 4, a flyby mission to Mars, after the Mars probe was successful it was repurposed to flyby Venus. Though missing the camera from the original purpose
        the craft was still armed with experiments to determine the properties of Venusian atmosphere, measuring the pressure and temperature. The plan, at first, was to flyby Venus at around 8 000 kilometers (5 000 miles) though that was changed for a much higher,
        75 000 kilometer (47 000 mile) flyby to make sure the unsterilized probe wouldn\'t crash into the surface of the planet. The course correction on the way set the final closest approach at 4 000 kilometers (2 500 miles). Mariner 5 detected no magnetic field, and
        measured much higher values for surface level atmosphere pressure and temperature than was returned by Venera 4, contesting the claims then put forward by the USSR that their probe reached the surface of the planet. The contact was lost on 4th of December 1967,
        though it returned contact briefly on 14th of October 1968 again, further contact attempts were cancelled on 5th of November of the same year.</string>
    <string name="kosmos_167">\nKosmos 167</string>
    <string name="kosmos_167_text">\nLaunched on 17th of June 1967 by USSR, the mission intended to land on Venus, the craft failed to leave Earth\'s orbit after the transplanetary stage motor was not cooled down prior to ignition. The probe reentered the atmosphere
        25th of June 1967.</string>
    <string name="venera_5">\nVenera 5</string>
    <string name="venera_5_text">\nLaunched on 5th of January 1969 by USSR, based on the previous design of Venera 4, the capsule was reinforced and the instruments tuned in to provide more precise values from the atmosphere of Venus. It has reached its destination on
        16th of May 1969, using its smaller parachutes than its predecessor it allowed to descend farther into the atmosphere to reach the crush depth before running out of power. The probe returned data every 45 seconds for 53 minutes, the results confirmed the findings
        of the previous mission.</string>
    <string name="venera_6">\nVenera 6</string>
    <string name="venera_6_text">\nLaunched on 6th of January 1969 by USSR, short of few differences in the devices that it carried it was virtually the same as Venera 5. It entered Venusian atmosphere a day later than the previous craft and just like it returned data
        every 45 seconds but for 51 minutes. One of the instruments hasn\'t worked properly, but every other result underlined the findings of Venera 5.</string>
    <string name="venera_7">\nVenera 7</string>
    <string name="venera_7_text">\nLaunched by USSR on 17th of August 1970, the craft was designed as a lander for Venus, with the reinforced structure and additional weight that it gained with upgraded specifications the experiments were severely limited. After a successful flight
        it had entered Venusian atmosphere on 15th of December 1970. At first everything went as planned, the parachute deployed partially followed by a full deployment some time later, with the fall slowed down significantly the chute failed and the lander went into a free-fall.
        Hitting the surface much faster than anticipated, at around 17 m/s (59 km/h; 37 mph) the contact was almost completely severed. Only a week later after close examination of the recording tapes it was discovered that the transmission continued for over 20 minutes on the surface,
        the readings confirmed that the environment on the surface of Venus would be lethal for humans. It\'s suspected that the lander bounced on impact and rolled on its side, turning the strongest antenna away from Earth, leaving only a weak data stream back to the ground.</string>
    <string name="kosmos_359">\nKosmos 359</string>
    <string name="kosmos_359_text">\nLaunched by USSR on 22nd of August 1970 the main craft was meant as a lander, thus it was significantly reinforced than any other previous mission aimed at Venus. It was designed to handle up to 180 bar and temperatures of 580 degrees C
        that meant severe additions in weight which limited the scientific instruments that could have been carried along on the mission. After launch the burn meant to put the spacecraft on its path the engine of the upper stage failed to ignite properly, starting too late and
        going out too early. Stranded and unable to control it the orbit decayed on the 7th of November 1970, burning up in the atmosphere.</string>
    <string name="venera_8">\nVenera 8</string>
    <string name="venera_8_text">\nLaunched on 27th of March 1972 by USSR, the craft successfully got to Venus on July 22nd 1972, landing on the sunlit side of the planet. Data was received for 50 minutes and 11 seconds after which the craft succumbed to the harsh conditions on the
        surface. The lander confirmed earlier findings from Venera 7, namely the temperature and pressure on the surface, while at the same time delivering new information. For example it revealed that the light level is suitable for surface level photography, as well as that the clouds
        end fairly high up in the atmosphere.</string>
    <string name="kosmos_482">\nKosmos 482</string>
    <string name="kosmos_482_text">\nLaunched by USSR on 31st of March 1972 by USSR, separated into 4 pieces in orbit around Earth, two have fallen down onto New Zealand within 48 hours, two remaining pieces are still orbiting Earth. It\'s suspected they might reenter the atmosphere
        between 2023 and 2025.</string>
    <string name="venera_9">\nVenera 9</string>
    <string name="venera_9_text">\nLaunched on 8th of June 1975 by USSR, the craft consisted of two parts, a lander and an orbiter, each with their own mission. While the lander was destined to measure the atmosphere chemicals and taking the first ever photograph of another world the
        orbiter would become the first man made object to achieve orbit around Venus. The lander operated on the ground for 53 minutes during which it has taken a black and white picture of the surface of Venus, it was originally intended to be a 360 panoramic shot alas one of the covers
        on the camera failed to deploy fully, limiting the view range to 180 degrees. The orbiter was used as a communications relay for the lander, as well as photographing the planet in ultraviolet. The orbiter stopped transmitting after a few months, their orbit decayed since though the
        exact date is unknown as it has not been traced since it has ceased transmission.</string>
    <string name="venera_10">\nVenera 10</string>
    <string name="venera_10_text">\nLaunched on 14th of June 1975 by USSR, the mission profile was identical to Venera 9 and the results just as similar; down to one of the camera covers not deploying properly giving only 180 degrees out of expected 360 for the picture. Landing was made on
        Otober 23rd 1975, a day after Venera 9\'s lander made planetfall.</string>
    <string name="pioneer_venus_1">\nPioneer Venus 1</string>
    <string name="pioneer_venus_1_text">\nLaunched on 20th of May 1978 by USA, it was 1 of 2 spacecraft incorporated into Pioneer Venus Project with its sistership launching a couple months later. The probe reached Venus and entered into orbit around it on 4th of December 1978,
        the first american spacecraft to do so. It used radar to map out the topographical features of the surface, as well as scanned the atmosphere revealing near continuous lightning in the cloud cover, infrared imaging also showed an atmospheric clearing over the north pole.
        While the mission was expected to last 8 months the craft operated until 8th of October 1992 when it burned up in the atmosphere after running out of propellant.</string>
    <string name="pioneer_venus_2">\nPioneer Venus 2</string>
    <string name="pioneer_venus_2_text">\nLaunched on 2nd of August 1978 by USA, it was the second spacecraft in the Pioneer Venus Project. It consisted of 4 probes, 1 large one and 3 identical smaller ones. The craft arrived at Venus without issue in November 1978 the large probe was
        deployed first, on 16th of November, with the small ones following on the 20th. All 4 probes entered within minutes of each other on 9th of December 1978, they weren\'t expected to survive the impact. The large probe was the only one equipped with parachutes, still
        transmission from it stopped at the moment of impact. The small probes did not have any means of slowing down, against all odds though one of the probes survived the impact. Transmissions were received from it for 67 minutes before the lack of power, temperature and pressure
        ended it. The main spacecraft entered the atmosphere around an hour and a half after the probes and burned up in the atmosphere.</string>
    <string name="venera_11">\nVenera 11</string>
    <string name="venera_11_text">\nLaunched on 9th of September 1978 by USSR, the mission consisted of 2 craft, a lander and its flight carrier. The lander carried equipment to study the temperature, as well as the chemical composition for the atmosphere and soil. The soil scanner failed,
        though the craft did bring back data of lightning as well as carbon monoxide at low altitudes. Data was received for 95 minutes until the flight carrier left the range; it didn\'t go into orbit, merely a flyby. The carrier went onto a heliocentric orbit and returned data of gamma bursts,
        the first such catalog. The mission was declared finished in February 1980, with the last gamma ray burst data received in January that year. Venera 11 remains in a heliocrentric orbit.</string>
    <string name="venera_12">\nVenera 12</string>
    <string name="venera_12_text">\nIdentical to Venera 11, from the equipment on the lander to the mission of the carrier being only a flyby above the planet. Launched on 14th of September 1978, the lander got to Venus on 21st of December 1978, transmitted while the main rocket was in range.
        The carrier continued on to a heliocentric orbit assisting Venera 11 with the gamma burst cataloging. The carrier\'s mission was declared finished on 18th of April 1980.</string>
    <string name="venera_13">\nVenera 13</string>
    <string name="venera_13_text">\nLaunched on 30th of October 1981 by USSR, together with the identical Venera 14 that launched just a few days later, were a pair of spacecraft designed to take advantage of the 1981 launch window to Venus, landing on the planet on 1st of March 1982. The lander
        tested the compressibility of the soil with spring-loaded arms, as well as cameras to take a panoramic picture of the environment. A drill was used to extract a sample of the soil, using x-ray radiation to determine what type of rock it is made out of, in addition to a set of microphones
        used to record the wind noises, in hope to measure its speed, it was the first ever recording of sound from another planet. The lander lasted for 127 minutes, the design predicted a lifespan of only 32.
        \n\nThe rest of the rocket was used as a relay, after leaving Venus it continued to make observations on x-ray and gamma spectrum, the bus continued to operate and send data until at least 25th of April 1983</string>
    <string name="venera_14">\nVenera 14</string>
    <string name="venera_14_text">\nLaunched on 4th of November 1981 the probe reached Venus in March, the lander\'s final descent on 5th of March 1982. Following a successful landing the craft did the same experiments as its predecessor just a few days back with one notable, and humorous, exception.
        One of the camera caps fell exactly where the spring loaded arms would go to, so the craft measured the compressibility of the cap rather than the Venusian soil. It lasted for 57 minutes, 25 minutes longer than it was designed to survive.
        \n\nThe bus of the craft went on into a heliocentric orbit and just like its predecessor provided data on x-ray and gamma spectrum, with it operating until at least 9th of April 1983.</string>
    <string name="venera_15">\nVenera 15</string>
    <string name="venera_15_text">\nLaunched on 2nd of June 1983 by USSR, together with the identical Venera 16 that launched a few days after it, were a pair of probes designed to orbit Venus in a polar orbit and use radar to map out the surface of the planet. Inserting into orbit on 10th of October
        1983, a day before its sibling, the crafts started to map out the northern hemisphere of Venus, from the pole down to about 30 degrees N latitude. The orbit was shifted by about 4 degrees in relation to Venera 16 which allowed the areas to be remapped if deemed necessary. Over 8 months of mapping
        approximately 25% of the surface was mapped. The last contact with the probe was on 5th of January 1985</string>
    <string name="venera_16">\nVenera 16</string>
    <string name="venera_16_text">\nLaunched on 7th of June 1983 by USSR, it successfully got to Venus and got inserted into a polar orbit, with a 4 degree deviation from Venera 15, and helped it map the surface of the planet. The last contact with the probe was on 13th of June 1985.</string>
    <string name="vega_1">\nVega 1</string>
    <string name="vega_1_text">\nLaunched on 15th of December 1984 by USSR, Vega 1 and Vega 2 were a two target mission, each carrying a lander and a balloon for Venus, with the main part of the spacecraft intending to use Venus for a gravity assist to research the Halley\'s Comet.
        The craft got to Venus on 11th of June 1985, the lander and balloon probe encased in a capsule was let go into the atmosphere, after separating excessive turbulence made the lander instruments deploy too soon, at around 20 km (12 miles) above the surface, only one successfully returned data.
        \n\nThe balloon, after separation, was inflated at around 50 km (31 miles) above the surface, rising and staying at between 53 and 54 km afterwards, it glided for over 11 000 km (6800 miles) above the surface, around 30 % of the circumferance of the planet. The balloon gathered data on
        the middle, most active layer of the atmosphere, getting its pressure, temperature, lightning, illumination levels, and cloud properties.
        \n\nFollowing the relaying of information from the lander and the balloon the bus of the craft went forward to meet up with the Halley\'s Comet with Vega 2 close behind. For 3 days both crafts made over 1500 pictures of the comet, giving us a lot of information on the comet, how large the nucleus
        is, its rotation period and what the comet consists of.
        \n\nVega 1 ran out of propellant on 30th of January 1987</string>
    <string name="vega_2">\nVega 2</string>
    <string name="vega_2_text">\nLaunched on 21st of December 1984, after an uneventful flight towards Venus the descent module containing the lander and the balloon detached from the mothership, entering the atmosphere on 15th of June 1985. Both of them reached their destinations without an issue,
        the lander completed its descent, landing on the night side of the planet no images were taken. The lander itself was identical to the earlier missions from Venera program. It transmitted from the surface for 56 minutes.
        \nThe balloon unfurled as expected, at the height of around 50 kilometers (31 miles), before floating back up to the height of between 53 and 54 kilometers (around 33 miles). It has traveled at a steady pace and altitude, floating for 2 days, until 17 of June, and over 11 000 kilometers (6 800 miles)
        when it lost contact with the ground. It is not known how much farther it went after that.
        \n\nThe bus went forward with the gravity assist manoeuvre and followed Vega 1 to intercept Halley\'s Comet, making plenty of photographs and measurements in the progress. After the 3 days spent around there it went back into a heliocentric orbit, the idea of a distant flyby of another comet was
        considered, alas the idea was shot down due to the shortage of fuel. Instead the craft was sent forward and into tails of three other comets and measured the dust therein.
        \n\nContact with the craft was lost on 24th of March 1986, it remains on a heliocentric orbit.</string>
    <string name="magellan">\nMagellan</string>
    <string name="magellan_text">\nThe Magellan spacecraft was designed under the principle of saving as much as possible, as such it was built out of spare parts from previous missions. It had parts from Voyager, Pioneer, Galileo, Mariner and others. Ending an 11 year break in US deep space probes Magellan
        was the first to be launched from the cargo bay of a space shuttle. Launched on the 4th of May 1989 the probe was released from the bay on the following day and started its journey to Venus.
        \n\nIt arrived at its destination on 10th of August 1990. After 2 anomalous contact outages and 1 preventative software update upload, on 15th of September 1990, Magellan started its primary mission: to map the surface of Venus. The craft operated in 243 day cycles, synced up with the Venusian rotation speed,
        the first 2 were focused on radar mapping the surface, completing most of it (96%, with 83% in the first cycle alone), a third cycle used stereo imaging, bringing the total surface mapped to 98%. Another 3 cycles were conducted, mostly focused on gravity of Venus, completing the map alongside those experiments.
        \n\nThe results of Magellan\'s mapping showed that most of Venusian surface is covered in lava flows, additionally, despite extreme temperature and pressure on the surface it was established that the complete lack of water made erosion a very slow process. It meant that surface features could last for hundreds of
        thousands of years mostly untouched.
        \n\nThe craft was commanded to dive into the atmosphere on 13th of October 1994, burning up and finishing one of the most successful deep space exploration missions ever.</string>
    <string name="venus_express">\nVenus Express</string>
    <string name="venus_express_text">\nLaunched on 9th of November 2005 by ESA, the probe was tasked with researching more of the Venusian atmosphere, among others, from a near polar orbit. Getting to Venus on 11th of April 2006, the engine fired putting the craft on an orbit, the first european probe to do so.
        It took until 7th of May 2007 to achieve the desired orbit for the probe, though experiments were already running in the meantime. Initially it was supposed to last not longer than 500 Earth days, but the mission was extended on 5 separate occasion, ending up going on until 2015. One of the first achievements
        was a complete temperature of the southern hemisphere of Venus, that was achieved by December 2006. Other achievements included the discovery of proof for past oceans on the surface, as well as, in 2011, a layer of ozone that was determined to exist thanks to the data delivered by the probe.
        \n\nThe orbit was constantly being adjusted, raised and lowered at different points in time, in November 2014 it left the craft with barely any fuel to spare for last maneuvers, they were planned for the middle of the month, alas the propellant ran out mid execution, pairing that with patchy signal from the probe
        Venus Express continued to decay its orbit naturally, sped up by the atmospheric drag present in the lower parts of the orbit. The last signal was received on 19th of January 2015, it\'s believed the probe burnt up in the atmosphere not long after.</string>


    <!-- STRINGS FOR THE ONGOING VENUS MISSIONS -->
    <string name="akatsuki">\nAkatsuki</string>
    <string name="akatsuki_text">\nLaunched on 20th of May 2010 by Japan, the probe was meant to study the properties of Venusian atmosphere as well as research how the clouds move and interact with each other.
        Initial plan was to insert the craft into orbit around Venus on 6th of December 2010, but the main engine of the probe developed an issue that caused the exhaust of the engine to be too hot, damaging some parts.
        The burn lasted 3 out of the predicted 12 minutes needed to insert into the orbit, and sent the probe back around the sun for the next 5 years.
        \n\nAnother attempt was possible on 7th of December 2015, with all excess weight vented out of the probe JAXA used attitude control thrusters to insert the probe into orbit, due to low power of those thrusters
        the orbit was much longer than the planned one, taking 10 days to go around instead of the planned 30 hours of the original idea. Still, the mission continued, with pictures of the planet returning as well as the
        results of observations of the night side of the planet calling into question the existence of lightning bolts in the atmosphere as no optical proof of them were detected from orbit.
        \n\nAmong other discoveries Akatsuki discovered something akin to Earth\'s jet stream along the equatorial region as well as signs of highly absorbant material, like water, between the middle and top layer of the atmosphere.
        The probe continues to be active as of February 2021.</string>

    <!-- STRINGS FOR DETAILS OF EARTH -->

    <string name="earth_rundown">The third planet in our solar system, the biggest of all rocky planets and fifth biggest overall.
        \nThe only planet not named after a Roman god or goddess, instead the name is a Germanic word.
        \nIt is so far the only planet we know of that harbors life as we know it.</string>
    <string name="earth_sizes_and_distances_text">With a radius of 6,371 kilometers (3,959 miles) Earth is the biggest of the 4 planets nearest to the Sun, outgrowing the second Venus by around 300 km (180 miles).
        \nThe average distance between it and the Sun is 150 million kilometers (93 million miles), or one Astronomical Unit.</string>
    <string name="orbit_and_rotation_earth_text">One full orbit takes 365.24 days.
        \nOne rotation on the axis of the planet takes 23.9 hours to complete.
        \nThe tilt of Earth comes at 23.4 degrees, making seasons possible.</string>
    <string name="history_of_earth_text">Earth is around 4.5 billion years old, forming alongside other bodies in our solar system.
        \nAt first believed to be a flat disk the shape of our planet was confirmed as a sphere with the return of the expedition of Magellan in 16th century, even before, in ancient times, there were calculations that were remarkably accurate for the size of our home.</string>
    <string name="internal_structure_of_earth">Earth has a metallic core about 1,221 km (759 miles) thick with an inner core of 2,300 kilometers (1,400 miles) then a liquid mantle above it.
        \nThe surface of the planet is full of volcanoes, most of which are underwater.
        \nEarth has plenty of valleys and mountains, the tallest being Mount Everest, is 8.8 kilometers high (29,000 feet).</string>
    <string name="the_inside_of_earth">The inside of Earth</string>
    <string name="atmosphere_of_earth">Earth\'s atmosphere consists of 78 percent nitrogen, 21 percent oxygen, and 1 percent other gases such as argon, carbon dioxide and neon.
        \nComing it at around 100 kilometers thick the atmosphere around our planet protects us from meteors striking the surface and doing serious damage as well as keeps the temperature on the surface stable.</string>
    <string name="earth_live">See Earth live</string>

    <!-- STRINGS FOR DETAILS OF MARS -->

    <string name="ended_mars_mission_count">36 missions ended (including 19 failures and 5 partial failures)</string>
    <string name="ongoing_mars_mission_count">11 missions ongoing</string>
    <string name="mars_rundown">Fourth planet of our solar system, known for its red hue thanks to the oxidized iron in the surface.
        \nThe atmosphere is around 100 times thinner than the one on Earth, dominated by CO2
        \nDue to the elliptical shape of the orbit the seasons on Mars aren\'t of equal length like they are on Earth.</string>
    <string name="mars_sizes_and_distances_text">With a radius of 3,390 kilometers (2,106 miles) Mars is around half of Earth\'s size, the entire surface area of the red planet roughly matches the combined land area on Earth.
        \nThe average distance between it and the Sun is 228 million kilometers (142 million miles).</string>
    <string name="orbit_and_rotation_mars_text">Martian days are comparable to those on Earth, 24.6 hours on Mars, 23.9 hours on Earth.
        \nMars has a rather elliptical orbit around our parent star, that combined with a tilt of 24 degrees (similar to Earth\'s 23.4) means that seasons are a thing, but they are not roughly equal length like on here.
        \nSpring in the north lasts 194 sols (Martian days), summer goes on for 178, autumn for 142 and winter takes 154.
        \n A single full rotation of Mars around the Sun takes 687 Earth days.</string>
    <string name="history_of_mars_text">Mars is around 4.5 billion years old, forming alongside other bodies in our solar system.
        \nOne of 5 planets visible with the naked eye, recorded observations of Mars go back 4000 years to ancient Egypt charting the planet\'s movement on the sky.
        \nThe first observations with a telescope was done with Galileo in the 17th century. Although uncertain of his success in determining martian phases he did note that it shrunk slightly during his observation.</string>
    <string name="internal_structure_of_mars">Mars, like other terrestrial planets, has a metallic core between 1,500 to 2,100 kilometers (930 and 1,300 miles) thick with a rocky mantle above it.
        \nMars is home to the biggest volcano in the solar system, Olympus Mons, it\'s 3 times taller than Mount Everest.
        \nThe largest valley on Mars, Valles Marineris, stretches on longer than the length of United States, more than 4,800 kilometers (3,000 miles). This Martian canyon is 320 kilometers (200 miles) at its widest and 7 kilometers (4.3 miles) at its deepest..</string>
    <string name="the_inside_of_mars">The inside of Venus</string>
    <string name="atmosphere_of_mars">Mars\' atmosphere consists mainly of CO2, but it\'s extremely thin, making any heat that gets to the surface of the planet dissipate nearly immediately.
        \nIf the temperature on the very surface reaches 24 degrees Celsius or 75 degrees Fahrenheit then just 2 meters (6-7 feet) up it would drop to 0 degrees Celsius or 32 degrees Fahrenheit.
        \nThere are sandstorms on Mars, the winds can kick up dust creating a cloud that covers the entirety of the surface and it can take months for everything to settle back down.</string>

    <!-- STRINGS FOR PAST MARS MISSIONS -->

    <string name="mars_1m_1">Mars 1M No.1</string>
    <string name="mars_1m_1_text">\nLaunched by USSR on 10th of October 1960 the spacecraft failed to reach orbit around Earth, ending up in a suborbital flight. It has disintegrated in the reentry.</string>
    <string name="mars_1m_2">\nMars 1M No.2</string>
    <string name="mars_1m_2_text">\nLaunched by USSR on 14th of October 1960 the rocket failed to reach orbit around Earth due to a problem with cryogenic material, making one of the engines impossible to start.</string>
    <string name="mars_2mv4_1">\nMars 2MV-4 No.1</string>
    <string name="mars_2mv4_1_text">\nLaunched by USSR on 24th of October 1962 the craft successfully reached orbit, though a technical problem and a leak caused the main engine to explode, destroying the spacecraft.</string>
    <string name="mars_2mv3_1">\nMars 2MV-3 No.1</string>
    <string name="mars_2mv3_1_text">\nLaunched by USSR on 4th of November 1962 the probe reached low Earth orbit successfully though a problem developed as cavitation developed in some parts, causing vibrations that damaged electric systems,
        preventing the craft from firing towards its destination.</string>
    <string name="mars_1">\nMars 1</string>
    <string name="mars_1_text">\nFirst soviet spacecraft with Mars as destination to get past low Earth orbit. Launched on 1st of November 1962 the probe left orbit and directed itself towards an encounter with Mars. A couple days into its interplanetary
        journey it was noticed that there was a leak, forcing the craft to switch to a secondary stabilization system. On 21st of March 1963 the probe ceased sending signals back to Earth, with the probable cause being failure to orient the antenna properly.
        The craft is suspected to have its closest approach to Mars on 19th of June 1963.</string>
    <string name="mariner_3">\nMariner 3</string>
    <string name="mariner_3_text">\nLaunched on 5th of November 1964 by USA the probe got to orbit without an issue, however a problem with a fairing that failed to detach from the craft made it impossible to extend its solar panels. Though ground
        control tried to find a workaround their efforts were too late, the probe ran out of power after only 8 hours of flight and the mission had to be called off.</string>
    <string name="mariner_4">\nMariner 4</string>
    <string name="mariner_4_text">\nIdentical to Mariner 3 in terms of construction, it was launched on 28th of November 1964 by USA the probe had a successful voyage from Earth to Mars with two of its experiments failing en route.
        The probe returned the first pictures of Mars just before its closest approach, as well as using its radio signals to measure the pressure on the surface of the planet giving valuable insight to how a possible lander would have to be constructed.
        The contact was maintained until 1st of October 1965, the probe was reactivated 2 years later in October 1967 to test some attitude control for Venera 6, this lasted until December that year.</string>
    <string name="zond_2">\nZond 2</string>
    <string name="zond_2_text">\nLaunched on 30th of November 1964 by USSR Zond 2 was supposed to become the first man made object to impact the surface of Mars. It successfully was placed on track to Mars though due to problems with solar panels not
        deploying fully the craft was denied full power which made it miss some of its planned burns to put it on an impact trajectory, with contact being lost in May 1965. The probe flew by Mars on 6th of August 1965.</string>
    <string name="mariner_6">/nMariner 6</string>
    <string name="mariner_6_text">/nLaunched on 25th of February 1969 by USA, it was first of an identical pair of probes (the second one being Mariner 7) designed for a flyby of Mars. The probes scientific suite was focused fully on the red planet,
        there were no instruments present to research interplanetary space. The probe took 24 pictures of Mars during its closest approach, as well as measured surface pressure, temperature and atmosphere composition. The on board instruments indicated
        that the south polar cap consisted of solid carbon dioxide.
        \n\nThe probe was in contact with Earth until mid 1971.</string>
    <string name="mariner_7">\nMariner 7</string>
    <string name="mariner_7_text">\nLaunched on 27th of March 1969 Mariner 7 succeeded in getting into a trajectory towards Mars. On 30th of July 1969 the crafts antenna signal was lost by the tracking station designated to it, with the search efforts
        being helped by another tracking station. The probe was found and a secondary antenna was activated that worked well until the end of the mission. It was speculated that the problem with signal was due to a micro-meteor impact or a battery explosion.
        \n\nDespite issues with positioning the probe took over 110 pictures of Mars, with 3 of them showing Phobos. Mariner 7 measured surface pressure and temperature of the planet.
        \n\nData was received until mid 1971.</string>
    <string name="mars_2m_no521">\nMars2 2M No.521</string>
    <string name="mars_2m_no521_text">\nLaunched on 27th of March 1969 by USSR, the rocket never left Earth\'s atmosphere. A problem with the engine of the 3rd stage started a fire that caused the craft to break up.</string>
    <string name="mars_2m_no522">\nMars2 2M No.522</string>
    <string name="mars_2m_no522_text">\nLaunched on 2nd of April 1969 by USSR, one of the first stages caught fire right after liftoff, the rocket flew for around 30 seconds before it lost control due to fire, crashing down 48 seconds after launch.</string>
    <string name="mariner_8">\nMariner 8</string>
    <string name="mariner_8_text">\nLaunched on 9th of May 1971 by USA, the first of two probes meant to study Mars from its orbit the rocket lost control shortly after launch, falling north of Puerto Rico, the problem was traced to a faulty circuit.</string>
    <string name="kosmos_419">\nKosmos 419</string>
    <string name="kosmos_419_text">\nLaunched on 10th of May 1971 it was meant to overtake Mariner 8 and 9 probes to become the first spacecraft to orbit the red planet. It had reached orbit around Earth, with the intention being for the main engine to fire an hour and
        half later, the timer was incorrectly set to one and a half year causing the rocket to fall back down only 2 days later.</string>
    <string name="mars_2">\nMars 2</string>
    <string name="mars_2_text">\nLaunched on 19th of May 1971 by USSR, it consisted of an orbiting component as well as a lander with a rover to study the martian surface and the composition of its atmosphere.The probe successfully executed the interplanetary flight to Mars,
        getting to it without any big trouble and inserting into orbit on 27th of November 1971. It was not, however, the first there. That title goes to Mariner 9 that although launched later than Mars 2 got to the red planet and completed its orbit first.
        \n\nWhen Mars 2 arrived on site Mars was under one of its planet-covering dust storms. Unable to reprogram the craft the lander was launched immediately after arrival, entering the atmosphere at a steep angle. The landing procedures did not fire, the lander
        crashed into the surface, becoming the first man made object to do so, although destroying it in the process.
        \n\nThe probe was meant to send back pictures of the martian surface, the dust storm made it impossible and a big part of the, already limited, memory capacity of the probe was taken up by photographs that did not show anything apart from the massive dust cloud.
        \n\nMission was shut down and called a success on 22nd of August 1972, the last transmissions were received in July 1972, Mars 2 remains in orbit to this day.</string>
    <string name="mariner_9">\nMariner 9</string>
    <string name="mariner_9_text">\nLaunched on 30th of May 1971 by USA, Mariner 9 was the second of the pair of probes meant to orbit around Mars, the first being Mariner 8 that launched and crashed a few weeks before.
        \n\nAfter a not eventful flight the probe entered orbit around Mars on 14th of November 1971, beating Mars 2 by 13 days to becoming not only the first man made object to achieve orbit around the red planet, but also the first probe to orbit another plnaet in general.
        \n\nRight after arrival the probe noticed that the planet is completely covered in dust, obscuring any possible photographs from showing the surface. It was only possible on 2nd of January 1972 when dust cleared to start taking photos. They showed many mountains,
        valleys, including Olympus Mons the tallest peak of the planet, as well as Valles Marineris, a system of canyons named after the probe.
        \n\nBy 11th of February 1972 NASA announced that the mission completed all of its objectives, though the probe continued to send data until the end of October that same year. All in all Mariner 9 returned over 7 300 photos of the surface, including 80 of martian moons.
        The probe is still in orbit today, expected to decay in the next 2 years.</string>
    <string name="mars_3">\nMars 3</string>
    <string name="mars_3_text">\nLaunched on 28th of May 1971 by USSR, the spacecraft flew to Mars without incident, getting into orbit on 2nd of December 1971. With a planned orbital period of 25 hours the fuel constraints meant it was not possible, as such the craft was put on
        an orbit of 12 days and 19 hours.
        \n\nThe descent module was released on the day of orbital insertion, reaching martian atmosphere after 4 hours. After performing an aerobreak, using parachutes and engines for final breaking the lander was the first soft landing on Mars. After 90 seconds it started transmitting
        data, though only 20 seconds into the transmission it was cut and never recovered. The possible reason is the dust storm that was still going on at the time of the landing interfering with the electronics.
        \n\nThe orbiter made pictures and calculated data from their observations from December 1971 to March 1972, revealing mountains, traces of hydrogen and oxygen, information on martian gravity and magnetic fields.
        \n\nThe transmission of that data, both from Mars 2 and Mars 3 went into August 1972, with both probes being deactivated in August, the last transmissions being received in July. Mars 3 is still in orbit.</string>
    <string name="mars_4">\nMars 4</string>
    <string name="mars_4_text">\nLaunched on 21st of July 1973 by USSR, the probe went into its interplanetary stage without an issue, though right after a mid-course correction burn two on board computers failed, ensuring the probe had no way to
        maneuver. That turned its intended mission of an orbiter into a flyby. It returned the pictures from the closest approach to Mars then went back into a heliocentric orbit where it remains to this day.
        \n\nLast contact with the probe was on 10th of February 1974.</string>
    <string name="mars_5">\nMars 5</string>
    <string name="mars_5_text">\nLaunched on 25th of July 1973 by USSR, the probe was successful in getting into orbit around Mars on 12th of February 1974. Right after the insertion the pressurized compartment with scientific instruments began to leak.
        The controllers on the ground believed it to be the result of a micrometeor impact. Last contact with the probe was on 28th of February 1974.
        \n\nThroughout its very short lifespan on the orbit of Mars it had returned 180 photographs, with only 43 of them being anywhere near usable, measured the composition of martian soil with gamma ray spectrometer as well as found an ozone layer at
        an altitude of around 30 kilometers (18 miles).</string>
    <string name="mars_6">\nMars 6</string>
    <string name="mars_6_text">\nLaunched on 5th of August 1973 by USSR, it consisted of a bus meant to perform a flyby of Mars and a lander. The craft executed the flight to the red planet without an issue, approaching it in March 1974.
        \n\nThe lander separated from its carrier on 12th of March 1974 and penetrated the atmosphere. The parachutes opened as planned, with the lander starting to transmit the data even earlier, but it ceased after less than 4 minutes,
        additionally an on board computer chip got corrupted en route to its intended target rendering most of the data that was returned completely unreadable.</string>
    <string name="mars_7">\nMars 7</string>
    <string name="mars_7_text">\nLaunched on 9th of August 1973 by USSR, it was very similar to Mars 6 in that it was also a flyby stage and a lander, with a successful travel to Mars that ended in March 1974.
        \n\nThe lander initially failed to detach from its probe, although eventually it was successful the delay and a failure in some other components caused the lander to miss the planet entirely, flying by Mars alongside its mothership.
        The failure was blamed on the crafts transistors.</string>
    <string name="viking_1">\nViking 1</string>
    <string name="viking_1_text">\nLaunched on 20th of August 1975 by USA, it consisted of an orbiter and a lander, with the lander being equipped to search for traces of life in the martian soil. The craft reached Mars safely, inserting itself
        into orbit on 19th of June 1976. A day later the lander was detached from the orbiter and descended to the surface.
        \n\n<b>The lander</b>
        \n\nThe lander transmitted high definition, colored photos of its surroundings as well as a 300 degree panorama. The craft recorded temperatures on the surface, although the seismometer was inactive, the testing for traces of life in the soil worked.
        The results of 4 tests returned 3 negative results and 1 weak positive, with the debate on whether it\'s a false positive or not continuing to this day. In addition the craft scanned the components of the soil, detecting an abundance of sulfur,
        clearly differentiating the samples from those that came from Earth or the Moon. The lander continued its work until 1982, sending daily and then weekly weather reports to Earth. In January 1982 it was renamed Thomas Mutch Memorial Station in honor of
        Thomas A. Mutch (1931-1980) the leader of the Viking imaging team who had died Oct. 6, 1980. The lander continued to function until November 1982 when ground control attempted to upload a software update to help with battery drain, instead they overrode
        the antenna direction system, contact was severed and never recovered.
        \n\n<b>The orbiter</b>
        \n\nThe orbiter took many pictures of Mars as well as Phobos and Deimos, as well as acted as a communication relay for the lander. It was deactivated on 7th of August 1980.</string>
    <string name="viking_2">\nViking 2</string>
    <string name="viking_2_text">\nLunched on 9th of September 1975 by USA, the craft was for all intents and purposes identical to Viking 1. The probe safely travelled to Mars, inserting into orbit on 7th of August 1976. The probe spent the next
        couple weeks photographing possible landing sites, with a site chosen the lander was released and touched down safely on 3rd of September 1976.
        \n\n<b>The lander</b>
        \n\nAfter touching down the lander sent through images from the surface, showing a surrounding completely different to what Viking 1 was seeing. Instead of hills, the area around the lander was nearly completely flat, the lack of any distinct
        features making locating the lander from orbit neigh impossible. Still the experiments went forward, with the search for life in the martian soil returning 2 positive results and 2 negative, though the positives are disputed. The lander continued
        to function until 12th of April 1980.
        \n\n<b>The orbiter</b>
        \n\nThe orbiter returned pictures of Mars from orbit, as well as pictures of the two moons. One of its notable feats include coming 28 kilometers (17 miles) of Deimos in May 1977 It continued to serve its purpose until it developed a leak,
        forcing the probe to be deactivated on 24th of July 1978.
        \n\nTogether the orbiters returned over 52 000 images of martian surface in better quality than ever before, mapping 97% of the surface while at it. The landers took and transmitted over 4 500 photos from the surface.</string>
    <string name="phobos_1">\nPhobos 1</string>
    <string name="phobos_1_text">\nLaunched on 7th of July 1988 by USSR, the mission was called and aimed at Phobos to avoid direct competition with previous US missions to the red planet. The craft successfully left Earth and continued on its way
        towards Mars, alas it would never get there.
        \n\nThe probe was meant to orbit around Mars and Phobos, including getting in extremely close proximity of the latter, down to 50 meters (160 feet) and dropping a "hopper" made to drill into and study the soil of the satellite.
        Mid flight between Earth and Mars, however, on 2nd of September 1988, the probe failed to return an expected signal. The problem was traced to a wrong command being sent to the probe, disabling its attitude control thrusters.
        The craft lost the lock on the sun, making it impossible to orient the solar panels properly, draining the batteries and killing the probe. As a result the ground control team commander got fired.</string>
    <string name="phobos_2">\nPhobos 2</string>
    <string name="phobos_2_text">\nThe last probe to be designed and launched by USSR before its collapse, Phobos 2 launched on 12th of July 1988, problems developed while it was transferring between Earth and Mars. The probe was built with 3 computers on
        board working together, any decision that had to be made required a majority, so 2 of them, to agree on a course of action. By the time the craft entered martian orbit 1 computer has died, another was malfunctioning, leaving only the last one
        as fully capable, meaning the probe could not do anything major.
        \n\nPhobos 2 has made 38 pictures of Phobos, mapping out around 80% of the surface and found no evidence of water being present. Its final maneuver was to drop two small landers on the surface, from the height of only 50 meters above the surface.
        sadly the contact with the craft was lost shortly before that final approach and failed to be reacquired, that happened on 27th of March 1989.</string>
    <string name="mars_observer">\nMars Observer</string>
    <string name="mars_observer_text">\nLaunched on 25th of September 1992 by USA, the probe was meant to study martian atmosphere, and its rotation, the magnetic field of the planet and the topography among others. The lander encountered Mars as planned,
        it was meant to insert into a high elliptical orbit on 24th of August 1993. On 21st of August 1993 the craft lost contact with ground control. Later investigation, with limited evidence, put forward a possible answer as a rapture of a fuel tank, 
        putting the craft into an uncontrollable spin and cancelling any automatic course instructions, though even that isn\'t a conclusive answer.</string>
    <string name="mars_global_surveyor">\nMars Global Surveyor</string>
    <string name="mars_global_surveyor_text">\nLaunched on 7th of November 1996 by USA, it was the first probe to use aerobreaking as a way to adjust its orbit into the correct path. its solar panels were designed to help in that regard, but after arriving
        at its destination one of the panels refused to open fully which meant that the original plan had to be modified. It took until February of 1999 to put the craft into the right orbit parameters to start the main mission, in the meantime it continued
        to send valuable data and detailed pictures of the surface, including observing the growth of a dust storm.
        \n\nOnce in near-polar orbit around the correct altitude the main mission could start. The craft used a laser beam to measure the topography of the terrain below it, for the first time ever mapping out the North Pole of Mars in that way. All in all
        over 500 billion pulses were sent down to the surface, creating a map more detailed than some areas on Earth. It sent some 240 000 images of the red planet to Earth.
        \n\nAfter serving its primary surface the probe continued to support future Martian missions, including future rovers, as a communications relay. The probe fell silent on 1st of October 2006, with the last transmission detected on the 4th, contact
        wasn\'t reestablished. NASA announced the mission to be over on 21st of November 2006, ending a decade long mission.</string>
    <string name="mars_96">\nMars 96</string>
    <string name="mars_96_text">\nLaunched on 16th of November 1996 by Russian Space Force, the probe carried a variety of instruments to research the red planet, including pellets of plutonium-238, although only 200 grams of it in total.
        The probe launched into space, though something went wrong between the third and fourth stage, making the craft lower its orbit down into Earth\'s atmosphere, making it reenter shortly thereafter, possibly crash-landing somewhere around Chile.</string>
    <string name="mars_pathfinder">\nMars Pathfinder</string>
    <string name="mars_pathfinder_text">\nLaunched on 4th of December 1996 by USA, the spacecraft had, apart from its scientific targets, been used as proof of several approaches to space exploration, the first being under the motto of "faster, better and cheaper"
        NASA was tasked with creating a martian exploration mission that did not cost as much as the Viking program, and Pathfinder succeeded in that, costing 1/15th of what Viking program did. It was also the first spacecraft to use inflatable cushions for landing.
        The mission consisted of a lander and a rover, with the former tasked with sending reports on weather and temperatures while the latter was supposed to research rocks around the landing zone.
        \n\nThe craft got to Mars without issue, starting its landing procedures on 4th of July 1997, safely going through all the phases of getting to the surface, from atmospheric entry through the deployment of parachutes and firing of the engines to
        the deployment of protective cushions. Once the craft was firmly on the ground the rover, Sojourner, was deployed. The area that the rover was put down on was suspected to be an ancient flood plain, which was supported by one of the rocks having
        properties reminiscent of flood rocks. Other samples had marks of volcanism, similar to andesite on Earth.
        \n\nBoth machines exceeded their expected lifespan, the rover in particular was meant to last only a week and it lasted as long as the lander itself. The last transmission received from Pathfinder was on 27th of September 1997, with NASA continuing
        to search for a signal up until March the following year. The mission was a resounding success, returning over 16 500 photographs of the surface, as well as millions of measurements of weather. After landing the lander was renamed Sagan Memorial Station.</string>
    <string name="mars_climate_orbiter">\nMars Climate Orbiter</string>
    <string name="mars_climate_orbiter_text">\nLaunching on 11th of December 1998 by USA, the probe was meant to lead a 2 year mission using water and dust particles to help with understanding of the martian climate and its history in that regard. Although 
    the probe successfully got in the vicinity of Mars an error with unit conversion (specifically: instructions being sent without units converted to what the probe was designed to understand), made the probe stray too close to the planet and burn up in the atmophere as the resutl.</string>
    <string name="mars_polar_lander">\nMars Polar lander</string>
    <string name="mars_polar_lander_text">\nLaunched on 3rd of January 1999 it consisted of a lander and two small impact probes that were supposed to work in tandem with the Mars Climate Orbiter mission as their relay back to Earth. The mission was designed to
    use rocket engines throughout the entire descent, rather than relaying on cushions like pathfinder did not too long before. The craft reached Mars on 3rd of December 1999 and entered atmosphere as planned, it wasn\'t heard from again.
    \n\nInvestigation that followed suggested that the vibrations caused by the deployment of lander legs were confused by the probe with impact, which turned off the engine prematurely and made the probe go into a free-fall that it had no way to recover from or survive.
    \n\nThe two small probes also failed to return any data after entering the atmosphere of the red planet.</string>
    <string name="nozomi">\nNozomi</string>
    <string name="nozomi_text">\nLaunched on 3rd of July 1998 by JAXA, the first probe sent to Mars by someone other than USA or Russia. The flight plan called for several flybys of the Moon and Earth to get the craft into the intended
        trajectory that would lead it towards its target of an elliptic orbit around the red planet, allowing it to study the planets atmosphere and the rate at which oxygen was fleeing it, together with surface research when closer to
        the planet.
        \n\nBad luck started after the last of the intended flybys, a faulty valve launched fuel out of the spacecraft, pairing it together with the maneuvers beforehand using more propellant than expected meant that the mission profile
        had to be redone to match the new situation, but that wouldn\'t be the end. Even with the new profile the probe was damaged by solar flares, frying some internal wiring and damaging a couple systems, in addition to that with the main engine
        inexplicably coming out damaged effectively caused the mission to end. The ground control had to reroute the vehicle away from Mars to ensure there wouldn\'t be a collision as with the original plan being in orbit the probe was not
        disinfected properly.
        \n\nNozomi went off to flyby Mars before ending up in heliocentric orbit, where it remains to this day.</string>
    <string name="spirit">\nSpirit</string>
    <string name="spirit_text">\nLaunched on 10th of June 2003 by USA, the first of a pair of rovers sent to Mars with a mission to research the surface rocks in locations that might have supported life in distant past of the planet.
        The rover was initially expected to traverse around 700 meters and last for 90 martian days, as it turned out Spirit held on for much longer than that.
        \n\nAfter landing on Mars on 4th of January 2004 the rover immediately went to work sending beautiful pictures of the surface and researching rocks around the landing site. 20 days into the mission a memory error forced a software update
        after which Spirit continued its mission normally.
        \n\nThe rover spent 2005 researching from Husband Hill, named after one of the astronauts of Columbia Shuttle final mission, finally reaching the summit in September Spirit made a 360 degree panorama of the surrounding terrain in true color.
        \n\nBy 2006 the rover was on its way to another hill, McCool. That eventually was cancelled due to one of the wheels locking up however. That event forced the rover to go in reverse, but it also had a silver lining as the wheel, while being
        dragged on the martian soiled uncovered a layer of silica rich material, indicating interaction between the soil and water.
        \n\nIn early 2007 NASA uploaded a software update that gave both Spirit and Opportunity the ability to decide whether to transfer photos or not, or extend the arm to take a closer look at a particular rock.
        \n\nFrom Summer 2007 to April 2009 Spirit experienced a drop in generated energy because of sandstorms on the surface of the planet, degrading the efficiency of its solar panels. Sadly, in May 2009 Spirit got stuck in a patch of soft soil,
        immobilizing it. After months of trying, unsuccessfully, to free the rover and with another wheel dead the mission was repurposed to act as a stationary science platform, with the plan calling for the vehicle to be tilted so its solar panels
        could take advantage of the sun while in winter but a desired tilt was never achieved.
        \n\nSpirit\'s career as a stationary platform lasted only a few months, from January 2010 to March 11th 2010 when the rover lost contact with Earth and hasn\'t regained it since.
        \n\nNASA called the mission finished on 25th of May 2011, Spirit traversed 7.7 kilometers (4.8 miles) and lasted for over 6 years.</string>
    <string name="opportunity">\nOpportunity</string>
    <string name="opportunity_text">\nNicknamed Oppy by NASA it was the second of the twin rovers sent to mars in 2003, it landed on Mars safely in January 2004, immediately going to work.
        \n\nThe next two years were spent on routine research tasks, with two highlights of finding an unusual meteorite in January 2005 and getting stuck in sand in May that same year. By June the rover was once again free to continue its tasks.
        \n\nThrough the rest of 2005 and until September 2006 Opportunity continued to drive forward towards its next target, Victoria Crater, stopping at another crater along the way for some more science.
        \n\nIn 2007 Oppy was hit with the same storm that clouded Spirit, and Opportunity got the worst of it, going so far as for NASA to suspend any activity indefinitely. In September 2007 the rover was back in the game and entered
        Victoria Crater, it stayed inside for around a year sending out plenty of data about the soil therein.
        \n\nThe rover\'s next target, Endeavour Crater, was so far away it took until 9th of August 2011 to get there, in which time Opportunity broke the record of longest continuous operation on Mars held up to that point by Viking 1
        on 20th of May 2010 with Spirit already inactive at that point.
        \n\nFor the next couple years Opportunity continued its experiments with martian soil, beating a few records while at it. On 16th of May 2013 Opportunity was officially the record holder for any NASA vehicle on another body, beating
        Apollo 17\'s lunar rover distance, that title got improved on 28th of July 2014 when the rover beat Soviet Lunokhod 2. In the meantime, on 4th of January 2010 Oppy celebrated the 10th anniversary of its arrival on Mars with martian wind
        clearing up its solar panels, increasing the power it received and increasing hopes for even more mission extensions.
        \n\nIn 2015 Opportunity got its memory reconfigured to work in RAM only mode following a failure of one of the memory banks that caused repeated system restarts interfering with usual progress. On 25th of March it was announced that
        Oppy has become the first man made vehicle to pass a marathon distance on another world, clocking in at 42 kilometers (26 miles).
        \n\nDuring 2016 the rover broke the record of the steepest climb on Mars, clocking at 32 degrees of inclination, on 10th of March.
        \n\nFebruary of 2017 was then Oppy was directed to head towards a gully dubbed Perseverance Valley, which it reached by May. After an issue with one of the wheels sticking out at a weird angle, and a problem with communications as Mars
        went behind the Sun the rover finally entered the valley in July. While inside Opportunity reported reduced energy gain from its solar panels.
        \n\nIn 2018 a historic, Mars-wide sand storm silenced the rover, with the last report received on 10th of June 2018.
        \n\nWith its life expectancy surpassed 60 times over NASA declared the mission finished and a resounding success ceasing its attempts to contact Oppy on 13th of February 2019.</string>
    <string name="phoenix">\nPhoenix</string>
    <string name="phoenix_text">\nLaunched on 4th of August 2007 by USA, it reached Mars on 25th of May 2008 becoming the first spacecraft to be photographed during its descent. It safely touched down in the Green Valley of Vastitas Borealis,
        a crater in the northern hemisphere. This was the first successful non-cushion assisted landing on Mars since Viking 2, 3 decades earlier.
        \n\n15 minutes after landing the solar panels extended and Phoenix started its process, sending a 360 degree panoramic shot that showed what was expected from the region- lots of rocks, not many hills or other recognizable features.
        \n\nFrom May to July the probe analyzed nearby soil, with the results of the experiments concluding that it indeed contained ice water, confirming that there is water on the Red Planet.
        \n\nPhoenix continued to function and send back more data to Earth, making NASA go back to Viking results to reconsider some more options thanks to the wealth of knowledge provided.
        \n\nThe last contact was received on 2nd of November 2008 with the martian winter upon it. It has not come back into contact since, with NASA ceasing any further attempts by 1st of December 2008
        \n\nIn 2010 images from one of the orbiting probes showed conclusively that the probe received severe damage, most likely from the buildup of CO2 ice on its solar panels, breaking them in the process.</string>
    <string name="phobosgrunt">\nPhobos-Grunt</string>
    <string name="phobosgrunt_text">\nLaunched on 8th of November 2011, an orbital malfunction cut the mission short on orbit around Earth, it reentered the atmosphere a little over a year later, in 2013.</string>

    <!-- STRINGS FOR ONGOING MARS MISSIONS -->

    <string name="mars_odyssey">\nMars Odyssey</string>
    <string name="mars_odyssey_text">\nLaunched on 7th of April 2001 by NASA, the probe holds the record for the longest continuous activity of a spacecraft around a celestial body that is not Earth.
        \n\nSince its orbital insertion in October 2001 Mars Odyssey\'s mission has been consistently extended every 2 years with different objectives in mind, for the first two years NASA studied the soil on the planet,
        discovering among others areas with high concentration of hydrogen suggesting water ice somewhere below the surface, in addition to noticing salts in some areas of land where water used to be abundant.
        As well as acting as a comms relay for other missions, including the rovers Spirit and Curiosity.
        \n\nBy 2016 the probe returned more than 208 000 pictures in visible light spectrum and over 188 000 pictures in thermal-infrared ranges.</string>
    <string name="mars_express">\nMars Express</string>
    <string name="mars_express_text">\nLaunched on 2nd of June 2003 by NASA, but under the control of ESA, Mars Express has been tasked with researching the martian climate, geology and to search for water on the surface.
        \n\nAs a result of its search the probe found enough ice water in the polar caps to flood the entirety of the planet, as well as extensive permafrost around the south pole. 
        \n\nThe probe also researched Mars\' moons and acted as a comms relay for landers and rovers on the surface. 
        \n\nThe probe also carried a lander named Beagle 2, named after the ship Charles Darwin used on his travels, it never sent back a signal about a successful landing and was considered lost until its discovery in 2015 when 
        it was noticed by one of the orbiting probes, after extensive photo processing the consensus on failing for the lander to get back to the ground control was attributed to one of the solar panels not deploying making it impossible for the
        antenna to extend.</string>
    <string name="mars_reconnaissance_orbiter">\nMars Reconnaissance Orbiter</string>
    <string name="mars_reconnaissance_orbiter_text">\nLaunching on 12th of August 2005 by NASA the MRO holds the second place for longest continuous operation around Mars.
        \n\nSince inserting into orbit on 11th of September 2006 MRO has delivered massive amounts of data. By 2010 NASA announced that it has surpassed 100 terabits, more than triple of all other deep space missions combined.
        In addition to that in 2015 it was announced that this probe alone delivered more data per week than every other active mission to the red planet combined.
        \n\nMRO returned a wealth on data on past water activity, including possible proof that water might still flow on Mars during the warmest months. The probe also served to assist other ongoing Mars missions in their tasks,
        including directing Opportunity around the crater it was in after determining the composition of some of the rocks. </string>
    <string name="curiosity">\nCuriosity</string>
    <string name="curiosity_text">\nLaunching on 26th of November 2011 by NASA, Curiosity was the biggest and heaviest rover to be sent to Mars yet, with its target being one of the most difficult terrain yet it proved quite the challenge.
        \n\nAfter arriving in August 2012 the rover was landed in a complex combination of aerobreaking, parachute and rocket assisted descent finished by slowly putting the actual rover on the ground with the help of a crane before
        its descent rocket flew off and crashed a safe distance away.
        \n\nIt took until 29th of August for the rover to complete all the tests and begin its normal functioning, researching the soil and rocks seeing if the area the mission is being conducted in would be good for life in the distant past.
        \n\nIt has succeeded in its mission many times over, finding water, salts, as well as nitrogen in the soil all of which would indicate that microbial life would be possible in the past with the surface of the planet being covered in water.</string>
    <string name="mangalyaan_mars_orbiter_mission">\nMangalyaan (Mars Orbiter Mission)</string>
    <string name="mangalyaan_mars_orbiter_mission_text">\nLaunched on 5th of November 2013 by India, the probe is the cheapest mission that was launched to Mars yet, it has successfully reached martian orbit on 23rd of September 2014,
        studying the red planet\'s atmosphere and soil as well as providing a test bed for technologies to be used in later missions.</string>
    <string name="maven">\nMAVEN</string>
    <string name="maven_text">\nLaunched on 18th of November 2013 by NASA, MAVEN (Mars Atmosphere and Volatile Evolution) was meant to study the upper portions of martian atmosphere and give us insight to how the gas therein
        is escaping into space thanks to solar wind and give us some more information that could serve to understand our own climate better.
        \n\nInserting into orbit around Mars on 21st of September 2014 MAVEN has repeatedly stooped down to between the upper and lower atmosphere of the red planet, discovering clouds of dust as well as an ultraviolet glow around
        the north pole area. It has since completed its primary mission, including taking a look at Phobos, at one time it had to make an adjustment to its orbit to avoid colliding with it.
        \n\nIt has been moved into a more stable orbit in 2019 in anticipation for the next NASA rover to arrive on the scene, indeed it has already been used to communicate with Curiosity. According to NASA it is planned to be
        used for a while longer, with enough propellant to last it until the 2030 and maybe even longer than that.</string>
    <string name="trace_gas_orbiter">\nTrace Gas Orbiter</string>
    <string name="trace_gas_orbiter_text">\nDesigned and directed by ESA, at first it was supposed to be in collaboration with NASA, but after budget cuts NASA abandoned the project so instead ESA partnered up with Roskosmos,
        launching on 14th of March 2016.
        \n\nThe mission\'s main task was to look for traces of Methane and other gases in the martian atmosphere, to find out whether the methane that was detected by previous missions was the result of geological or biological
        processing.
        \n\nArriving at mars on 19th of October 2016 the mission was inserted into orbit around the red planet, but it hasn\'t started its primary mission until 2018 using aerobreaking to circularize its orbit into satisfying heights.
         Since then the research on methane and other gasses was underway, with the first reports from 2019 stating there was no detection of methane in the martian atmosphere by the probe, despite the increased sensitivity.</string>
    <string name="insight">\nInSight</string>
    <string name="insight_text">\nLaunched on 5th of May 2018 by NASA, the mission was designed to burrow into the surface of the planet and answer some questions about how rocky planets in our solar system, and beyond formed, as well
        as just how exactly is Mars constructed on the inside.
        \n\nGetting to Mars in November 2018, the touchdown happened on the 26th. The burrowing instrument, nicknamed mole, has been used on the soil but an unexpected consistency of the regolith made it impossible for the instrument to go
        deeper than a few inches, it couldn\'t get enough friction to continue down. The team in control of the mole only called it quits on 5th of January 2021, admitting defeat but noting that this experience will surely come in handy in other missions.
        \n\nOther instruments worked just fine, including the first seismometer brought down to the surface of the red planet, with the first marsquake detected on 6th of April 2016. The lander also sends back daily, comprehensive reports on
        martian weather that are available to the public.
        \n\nAlong with InSight NASA launched 2 experimental probes called WALL-E and EVE, both the size of a suitcase the probes were a successful experiment that proved that smaller probes, at a fraction of a cost, are definitely possible.
        The probes performed a flyby of Mars and provided relays of communication from the InSight as it was landing before continuing to heliocentric orbit where they remain to this day. The last contact with them was 29th of December 2018 and 4th of January 2019 respectively.</string>


    <!-- STRINGS FOR DETAILS OF JUPITER -->


    <string name="ended_jupiter_mission_count">8 missions ended (no failures)</string>
    <string name="ongoing_jupiter_mission_count">1 mission ongoing</string>
    <string name="jupiter_rundown">The fifth planet in our solar system, the biggest of all planets, weighing more than twice as heavy as every other planet combined.
        \nFittingly named after the king of Roman gods.
        \nIt is home of the biggest ocean in the solar system, made of liquid hydrogen rather than water like on Earth.</string>
    <string name="jupiter_sizes_and_distances_text">With a radius of 69,911 kilometers (43,440 miles) Jupiter is the biggest planet in our solar system, 11 times the size of Earth and 317 times its mass.
        \nThe average distance between it and the Sun is 778 million kilometers (778 million miles), or 5.2 Astronomical Units.</string>
    <string name="orbit_and_rotation_jupiter_text">One full orbit takes 4,333 days, that\'s around 12 Earth years.
        \nOne rotation on the axis of the planet takes only 10 hours to complete, the shortest day of any planet.
        \nThe tilt of only 3 degrees makes seasons non existent in nearly all but name.</string>
    <string name="history_of_jupiter_text">Jupiter is around 4.5 billion years old, forming alongside other bodies in our solar system.
        \nObserved by Galileo in 1610 the astronomer discovered the 4 biggest moons of the jovian system, now known as Io, Europa, Ganymede and Callisto. That observation added substantial weight to abolishing the
        theory that everything would be orbiting around Earth.</string>
    <string name="internal_structure_of_jupiter">Jupiter\'s core is quite the mystery. We know that deep below the cloud cover of mostly hydrogen and helium, not unlike our sun, is a gigantic ocean of liquid hydrogen,
        the internal pressure below the surface might make the liquid conductive to be alike to a solid, allowing the massive magnetic field to be created, however we can\'t know for sure whether the very core is solid
        or simply a super dense continuation of the internal ocean.
        \nAs Jupiter is a gas giant there is no solid surface you could land on.</string>
    <string name="the_inside_of_jupiter">The inside of Jupiter</string>
    <string name="atmosphere_of_jupiter">Jupiter\'s atmosphere consists of 89.8% hydrogen, 10.2% helium. Close to the consistency of Sun\'s plasma, differing by near 15% with both.
        \nThe top part of the planet\'s internal structure is taken up by three layers of clouds of water and ammonia getting carried by masses of hydrogen and helium in the atmosphere, the famous red spot is a centuries old storm.</string>

    <!-- STRINGS FOR PAST JUPITER MISSIONS -->

    <string name="pioneer_10">\nPioneer 10</string>
    <string name="pioneer_10_text">\nLaunched by NASA on 2nd of March 1972, the probe was designed to last for around 21 months, until the encounter with Jupiter, it would go on to work for over 3 decades instead.
        \n\nPioneer 10 has several, possibly yet to be matched, first achievements in its name. It was the first to go beyond Mars, to go through the asteroid field, to fly by Jupiter, to go beyond Neptune, to go on an
        interstellar trajectory as well as the first to be powered fully by nuclear power.
        \n\nThe probe\'s life was an eventful one, after being sent into space it became the fastest man made object up to that point. Through the transition stage the only issues were with direct sunlight heating up the
        spacecraft, but it wasn\'t anything that would threaten the mission. During the encounter with Jupiter Pioneer 10 has measured its magnetic field, helping us understand just how big it is, as well as took marvelous
        photographs as well as plenty of data on it and its moons.
        \n\nRoutine contact was kept up until 1997, when it was reduced due to the budget, but intermittent contact was still available. The last time Pioneer 10 sent back data was on 23rd of January 2003. It became quite
        clear that the power source has decayed too much, not giving enough power to the antenna to transmit anymore.
        \n\nIn case the probe was ever captured by intelligent life it contains a plaque with information on humans as well as the location of Earth, the probe is on a general heading to encounter another star, but it would
        take some 2 million years before it gets there.</string>
    <string name="pioneer_11">\nPioneer 11</string>
    <string name="pioneer_11_text">\nLaunching on 6th of April 1973, the probe was a twin to earlier Pioneer 10, aimed to flyby Saturn by using Jupiter for gravitational assist.
        \n\nAfter a couple technical issues, thankfully none serious enough to actually stop the mission from progressing, Pioneer 11 flew by Jupiter around 3 times closer than its predecessor, and just as much faster establishing
        the new man-made-object speed record.
        \n\nFollowing that the probe was sent flying towards Saturn, conclusively proving that it indeed had its own magnetic field. During the flyby of the ringed planet Pioneer 11 made over 400 pictures of Saturn and its moons,
        measuring the temperature on the surface of Titan, as well as picturing it.
        \n\nAfter the encounter it flew on, towards interstellar space, aimed roughly towards the center of our galaxy, opposite direction to that of Pioneer 10. Passing the orbit of Neptune in 1990 it became the fourth spacecraft
        to do so, after its twin and Voyager 1 and 2.
        \n\nLast contact was made in 1995, first in September then November. It has been silent since.</string>
    <string name="voyager_1">\nVoyager 1</string>
    <string name="voyager_1_text">\nLaunched on 5th of September 1977 by NASA, it would become the first probe to leave our solar system, discover a ring around Jupiter, 2 new moons orbiting it, as well as a new ring around Saturn
        and 5 new moons.
        \n\nWhen Voyager 1 arrived at Jupiter it took photos every 96 seconds for a 100 hours, creating a time lapse of 10 jovian days. The photographs showed the atmosphere to be more turbulent than that seen by the Pioneer spacecraft,
        prompting a rethink of the atmospheric models for Jupiter as the ones that were then in use did not explain the new structures that Voyager 1 showed. Not only that, but pictures of moons around the planet showed Io to be one of the,
        if not the very most active body geologically, detecting several active volcanoes on the surface.
        \n\nThe flyby of Saturn was just as fruitful. It has delivered in discovery of several new satellites within the rings, as well as pictures of few moons, including a closer look on Titan which was determined to be a possible candidate
        for the very sort of chemistry that lead to the birth of life on Earth, as well as the fact that Titan might be the first body that isn\'t earth with liquid on the surface.
        \n\nDue to the required maneuvers to get close to Titan Voyager was not pushed towards Neptune and Uranus, instead being directed out of the system. NASA directed the on board camera back towards the system, Voyager took many iconic photos,
        including the famous "Pale blue dot" photograph.
        \n\nIn 2017 Voyager 1 crossed the boundary of interstellar space as the first human made object to do so, starting to measure it and send back data. It remains active as of February 2021.</string>
    <string name="voyager_2">\nVoyager 2</string>
    <string name="voyager_2_text">\nLaunched on 20th of August 1977 by NASA, despite being launched before Voyager 1 it was in orbit for a while before getting sent out into deep space. It is so far the first, and only, probe to study
        all 4 of gas giant planets in the outer parts of our solar system.
        \n\nBuilding on the data of Voyager 1, the probe flew by Jupiter, much closer than its predecessor. it has sent back pictures on all the moons that the previous probe has studied, including looking at Io for 10 hours on "volcano watch".
        Voyager 2 has discovered 4 new moons, new ring around the planet, as well as new information on the atmosphere, with over 17 000 pictures of all bodies combined.
        \n\nFollowing that the probe went forward to Saturn, a journey that took 2 years. Voyager 2 once again repeated the motions of its twin, capturing photographs of Saturn\'s moons and rings, giving us more insight into the planetary system
        of the second biggest planet around the Sun.
        \n\nNext the probe was aimed at Uranus, 4 and a half years later. Due to the planned encounter with Neptune later on Voyager 2 only had just over 5 hours to study Uranus and its moons, discovering 10 of them as well as 2 rings.
        The probe discovered the possibility of a boiling water ocean under the thick cloud cover, as well as delivering  measurements of wind speeds on the body.
        \n\nFinal planetary encounter before going on an interstellar trajectory was with Neptune. After another 4 years of flight Voyager 2 had the opportunity to discover 6 new moons, measure the wind speeds, as well as discover the dark
        spots on the clouds, photographing its largest moon, Triton.
        \n\nAfter leaving Neptune NASA officially renamed the mission of both Voyager 2 and its sibling into Voyager Interstellar Mission. The probe had its non essential instruments permanently turned off in November of 1998. During its flight
        the thrusters designed to control the way the probe is facing has been continually degrading, making it more and more difficult to ensure the antenna is pointing at Earth. Still, as of early 2021 Voyager 2 has continually returned valuable data 
        on interstellar space.</string>
    <string name="galileo">\nGalileo</string>
    <string name="galileo_text">\nLaunched on 18th of October 1989 by NASA it was the first probe to orbit Jupiter. After a flyby of Venus, Earth and an asteroid it has reached the vicinity of the planet and released an atmospheric probe it has been
        carrying to study the atmosphere therein directly.
        \n\nThe probe reached Jupiter in 1995 but before that, in 1994, it became the first spacecraft to observe an impact fo a comet with another body. On July 16th a comet struck Jupiter and thanks to the unique perspective of the probe it could,
        and did, deliver stunning photographs of the event.
        \n\nThe craft orbited Jupiter in a oval orbit, each designed to have a low point that would allow Galileo to flyby one of the moons and gather data on its tape recorder that was then sent back to Earth during the rest of the orbit.
        \n\nThe probes career was extended a few times, with the primary mission being done in 1997 and still more to learn NASA approved a 2 year extension focusing on Io, Europa and Jupiter\'s thunderstorms. Exploring Io meant crossing the immense
        radiation field around the biggest planet, which when done messed with on board computer facilitating the team on the ground to spend the entire night trying to bring it back, with success. Galileo returned data supporting the thesis of
        a liquid, underground ocean on Europa, getting pictures of a volcanic eruption on Io as well as giving us an insight to Jupiter\'s storms.
        \n\nThe mission ended in 2003, with Galileo plunging into the atmosphere just south of the equator, not being sterilized NASA didn\'t want to risk the probe crashing into, and possibly contaminating, Europe.
        \n\n<b>The atmospheric probe</b>
        \n\nGalileo carried with it a small probe meant to enter the gas giant\'s atmosphere and give us more information on it. Being released from the main probe when it was around 80 million kilometers (50 million miles) away from its target,
        the probe entered the atmosphere on 7th of December 1995, returning valuable data for around an hour. During the descent it has experienced temperatures up to 16 000 degrees Celsius (28 000 degrees Fahrenheit), atmosphere pressure 22 times
        greater than down on Earth, not to mention winds blowing as fast as 600 meters per second (around half a mile per second). The composition of the atmosphere was different than expected, nearly half as much helium was present than predicted,
        less water vapor as well as less lightning bolts.</string>
    <string name="cassiniHuygens">\nCassini-Huyegens</string>
    <string name="cassiniHuygens_Text">\nLaunched on 15th of October 1997, in cooperation between ESA and NASA, all in all 28 countries participated in some way to the mission, from providing the components
        to build the probe with to the ground controllers.
        \n\nAfter launching from Earth Cassini flew by Venus and used it for a gravity assist, allowing it to cross the asteroid belt but it got turned around with Sun\'s gravity.
        \n\nFollowing that the probe returned to the vicinity of Earth, flying by it and our Moon, taking series of calibration photos. With that done it was well on its way towards its first target, Jupiter.
        \n\nThe flyby of Jupiter took around half a year, allowing to take the clearest colored photo of the planet, as well as to research how the clouds were behaving in the atmosphere, the movement
        of the stripes in relation to each other as well as rising and sinking of the atmospheric features.
        \n\nEn route to Saturn the probe tested general relativity, with the help of the sun, with the most accurate measurements to date Einstein\'s theory had even more proof.
        \n\nDuring its years orbiting Saturn Cassini discovered 7 moons, though one of them was photographed by one of the Voyager probes when they were revalued. Furthermore the probe executed many flybys
        of the planet\'s moons, including Titan, which would be landed on later on in the mission with the small probe attached to Cassini. Among the important discoveries are the structure of Titan, possibly giving us
        insight to the early life of Earth as a planet, with many parallels from lakes and rivers to volcanoes. Additionally Enceladus has shown to have a jet of water ice coming from its north pole,
        revealing a subsurface liquid ocean that might be suitable for life.
        \n\nThe mission was extended twice, giving us many more flybys of Saturn\'s moons and rings, allowing even more data to be delivered back to Earth, including 350 pictures from the surface of Titan.
        \n\nCassini was disposed off by diving into the atmosphere of Saturn on 15th of September 2017, by most estimates being destroyed 45 seconds after the final transmition
        \n\n<b>Huyegens lander</b>
        \n\nThe lander was included with the mission, delivered to Titan and sent to the surface, successfully landing on it in January of 2005. The lander sent information out for over 2 hours, providing us with
        many photographs of its landing spot, showing pebbles and sand on a flat plain, but more interesting is the signs of recent liquid activity on the surface.</string>

    <!-- STRINGS FOR DETAILS OF SATURN -->


    <string name="ended_saturn_mission_count">4 missions ended (no failures)</string>
    <string name="ongoing_saturn_mission_count">0 missions ongoing</string>
    <string name="saturn_rundown">The sixth planet in our solar system, the second biggest of all planets, weighing more than twice as heavy as every other planet combined.
        \nNamed after the Roman god of agriculture and wealth.
        \nMade of helium and hydrogen, like Jupiter, and also like the earlier planet it has rings, but the rings around Saturn are way more impressive to say the least.</string>
    <string name="saturn_sizes_and_distances_text">With a radius of 58,232 kilometers (36,183 miles), 7 times the size of Earth and 95 times its mass.
        \nThe average distance between it and the Sun is 1.4 billion kilometers (886 million miles), or 9.5 Astronomical Units.</string>
    <string name="orbit_and_rotation_saturn_text">One full orbit takes 10,756 days, that\'s around 29 Earth years.
        \nOne rotation on the axis of the planet takes only 10.7 hours to complete, only slightly longer than Jupiter.
        \nThe tilt of over 26 degrees makes Saturn experience seasons just like Earth.</string>
    <string name="history_of_saturn_text">Saturn is around 4.5 billion years old, forming alongside other bodies in our solar system.
        \nObserved by Galileo in 1610 the astronomer observed the planet\'s rings, thinking they might be ears or 2 giant moons that orbit it. A couple years later, when he looked on it again, the rings weren\'t visable
        due to the planet\'s angle changing, now the rings were edge on. It took until 1695 when a Dutch astronomer concluded that Saturn had rings and discovered its biggest moon, Titan.</string>
    <string name="internal_structure_of_saturn">Saturn\'s core is most likely composed of nickel and iron. We know that deep below the cloud cover of mostly hydrogen and helium, not unlike our sun, is a gigantic ocean of liquid hydrogen,
        it\'s pretty much like Jupiter\'s core, but smaller.
        \nAs Saturn is a gas giant there is no solid surface you could land on. At the same time the internal situation, pressure, temperature, makes it impossible to go through the planet unscathed.</string>
    <string name="the_inside_of_saturn">The inside of Jupiter</string>
    <string name="atmosphere_of_saturn">Saturn\'s atmosphere consists of 75% hydrogen, 25% helium. There are traces of other gases like methane.
        \nThree layers of clouds exist, each composed of a slightly different material and different temperature. Lower the hydrogen and helium turn into liquids. There are gigantic storms between the clouds, some emerging on the surface, each bigger than the entirety of Earth.</string>


    <string name="large_text">
        "Material is the metaphor.\n\n"

        "A material metaphor is the unifying theory of a rationalized space and a system of motion."
        "The material is grounded in tactile reality, inspired by the study of paper and ink, yet "
        "technologically advanced and open to imagination and magic.\n"
        "Surfaces and edges of the material provide visual cues that are grounded in reality. The "
        "use of familiar tactile attributes helps users quickly understand affordances. Yet the "
        "flexibility of the material creates new affordances that supercede those in the physical "
        "world, without breaking the rules of physics.\n"
        "The fundamentals of light, surface, and movement are key to conveying how objects move, "
        "interact, and exist in space and in relation to each other. Realistic lighting shows "
        "seams, divides space, and indicates moving parts.\n\n"

        "Bold, graphic, intentional.\n\n"

        "The foundational elements of print based design typography, grids, space, scale, color, "
        "and use of imagery guide visual treatments. These elements do far more than please the "
        "eye. They create hierarchy, meaning, and focus. Deliberate color choices, edge to edge "
        "imagery, large scale typography, and intentional white space create a bold and graphic "
        "interface that immerse the user in the experience.\n"
        "An emphasis on user actions makes core functionality immediately apparent and provides "
        "waypoints for the user.\n\n"

        "Motion provides meaning.\n\n"

        "Motion respects and reinforces the user as the prime mover. Primary user actions are "
        "inflection points that initiate motion, transforming the whole design.\n"
        "All action takes place in a single environment. Objects are presented to the user without "
        "breaking the continuity of experience even as they transform and reorganize.\n"
        "Motion is meaningful and appropriate, serving to focus attention and maintain continuity. "
        "Feedback is subtle yet clear. Transitions are efﬁcient yet coherent.\n\n"

        "3D world.\n\n"

        "The material environment is a 3D space, which means all objects have x, y, and z "
        "dimensions. The z-axis is perpendicularly aligned to the plane of the display, with the "
        "positive z-axis extending towards the viewer. Every sheet of material occupies a single "
        "position along the z-axis and has a standard 1dp thickness.\n"
        "On the web, the z-axis is used for layering and not for perspective. The 3D world is "
        "emulated by manipulating the y-axis.\n\n"

        "Light and shadow.\n\n"

        "Within the material environment, virtual lights illuminate the scene. Key lights create "
        "directional shadows, while ambient light creates soft shadows from all angles.\n"
        "Shadows in the material environment are cast by these two light sources. In Android "
        "development, shadows occur when light sources are blocked by sheets of material at "
        "various positions along the z-axis. On the web, shadows are depicted by manipulating the "
        "y-axis only. The following example shows the card with a height of 6dp.\n\n"

        "Resting elevation.\n\n"

        "All material objects, regardless of size, have a resting elevation, or default elevation "
        "that does not change. If an object changes elevation, it should return to its resting "
        "elevation as soon as possible.\n\n"

        "Component elevations.\n\n"

        "The resting elevation for a component type is consistent across apps (e.g., FAB elevation "
        "does not vary from 6dp in one app to 16dp in another app).\n"
        "Components may have different resting elevations across platforms, depending on the depth "
        "of the environment (e.g., TV has a greater depth than mobile or desktop).\n\n"

        "Responsive elevation and dynamic elevation offsets.\n\n"

        "Some component types have responsive elevation, meaning they change elevation in response "
        "to user input (e.g., normal, focused, and pressed) or system events. These elevation "
        "changes are consistently implemented using dynamic elevation offsets.\n"
        "Dynamic elevation offsets are the goal elevation that a component moves towards, relative "
        "to the component’s resting state. They ensure that elevation changes are consistent "
        "across actions and component types. For example, all components that lift on press have "
        "the same elevation change relative to their resting elevation.\n"
        "Once the input event is completed or cancelled, the component will return to its resting "
        "elevation.\n\n"

        "Avoiding elevation interference.\n\n"

        "Components with responsive elevations may encounter other components as they move between "
        "their resting elevations and dynamic elevation offsets. Because material cannot pass "
        "through other material, components avoid interfering with one another any number of ways, "
        "whether on a per component basis or using the entire app layout.\n"
        "On a component level, components can move or be removed before they cause interference. "
        "For example, a floating action button (FAB) can disappear or move off screen before a "
        "user picks up a card, or it can move if a snackbar appears.\n"
        "On the layout level, design your app layout to minimize opportunities for interference. "
        "For example, position the FAB to one side of stream of a cards so the FAB won’t interfere "
        "when a user tries to pick up one of cards.\n\n"
    </string>
</resources>